COLTON OGDEN: All right.
科尔顿·奥格登：好的
Welcome to Lecture 9 of GD50.
欢迎来到GD50第九讲
Today's topic is Dreadhalls.
今天的主题是可怕的大厅
So last week we ventured into Unity, our first foray into 3D, and not only 3D,
因此 上周我们冒险进入了Unity 这是我们首次涉足3D领域 而且不仅是3D
but also just getting our heads and hands
但也只是让我们的头和手
around the Unity game engine, which is among Unreal and others
围绕着统一游戏引擎 它是虚幻和其他游戏中的
sort of the most popular game engines in use for 2D and 3d games.
这是2D和3D游戏中最流行的游戏引擎
And last week we did sort of a 2.5D style helicopter game whereby
上周我们做了一个2.5D风格的直升机游戏
everything was in 3D, but we were still aligning things based on just two axes,
一切都是3D的 但我们仍然只基于两个轴来对齐东西
the x and the y, I believe, possibly the z and the y.
X和y 我相信 可能是z和y
I don't remember, but two axes versus three axes.
我不记得了 但两把斧头对三把斧头
Today we'll actually be diving into using all three axes available to us
今天 我们实际上将使用我们可用的所有三个轴
in Unity 3D in the context of a game called Dreadhalls.
在Unity3D中的一款名为Dreadhalls的游戏的背景下
And so what Dreadhalls is--
所以恐怖大厅是什么--
it was a VR game, actually the first VR game
这是一款VR游戏 实际上是第一款VR游戏
that I ever played on the Oculus, the gear VR, Samsung Gear VR.
我曾经在Oculus Gear VR Samsung Gear VR上玩过
And it pits you in sort of this dark and eerie 3D maze
它让你置身于黑暗而诡异的3D迷宫中
where you don't really know what's going on.
你真的不知道发生了什么
And you can go around and get collectibles
你可以四处走走 拿到收藏品
and encounter creatures and stuff as you can see
和你看到的生物和东西相遇
in the bottom right screen shot there.
在右下角的屏幕截图中
Today's example is going to be a little simpler.
今天的示例将稍微简单一些
But it allows us to explore things like procedural maze generation
但它允许我们探索程序迷宫生成之类的事情
and first person camera control.
和第一人称相机控制
So last week recall we were using sort of a third person camera
上周我们使用了一种第三人称摄像机
whereby we were sort of far back on the scene.
我们就像是回到了现场很远的地方
Today we'll actually be using a first person camera
今天我们将使用第一人称相机
where the camera is effectively our eyes as if we were
摄像机实际上就是我们的眼睛 就好像我们是
walking around in the maze ourselves.
自己在迷宫里走来走去
Unfortunately, we won't be using a VR demonstration this week,
不幸的是 本周我们不会使用VR演示
but next week I hope to put together sort of a VR sampling
但下周我希望能做一个虚拟现实的样本
using this project so we can see how this works in VR
使用这个项目 这样我们就可以看到它在VR中是如何工作的
and how Unity's toolkit works in VR.
以及Unity的工具包在VR中是如何工作的
So some of the topics we'll be covering today--
所以我们今天要讲的一些话题--
we'll be talking about texturing.
我们将讨论纹理处理
So recall last week the helicopter and all of the items in our game
回想一下上周的直升机和我们游戏中的所有物品
were just sort of flat colors.
只是一种单调的颜色
They didn't really have any texture associated with them.
它们实际上并没有任何与之相关的质地
We'll talk about how to assign textures to materials
我们将讨论如何为材质指定纹理
and how to apply those materials to objects in our scene.
以及如何将这些材质应用于场景中的对象
We'll talk about materials and lighting, so not only materials but also
我们将讨论材质和照明 因此不仅材质 而且
the different kinds of lights that Unity supports and a few details about those.
Unity支持的不同类型的灯光以及有关这些的一些细节
We'll talk about, again, 3D maze generation,
我们将再次讨论3D迷宫的生成
so we'll have a simple but effective algorithm for creating a 3D data
因此 我们将有一个简单但有效的算法来创建3D数据
structure to represent our level as opposed to previously
结构来表示我们的级别 而不是以前的
where we had just a tile map that we could
我们只有一张瓷砖地图 我们可以
generate to give us the appearance of walking around
生成让我们看起来像是在四处走动
in some sort of 2D world.
在某种2D世界里
Now we'll actually perform a similar operation on Data, a 2D array.
现在 我们将实际对数据执行类似的操作 即2D数组
But we'll take that array and we'll actually create 3D blocks
但我们将使用该数组并实际创建3D块
and create a maze that we can walk through in 3D space, which
并创建一个我们可以在3D空间中漫步的迷宫
is kind of fun and interesting.
是一种有趣的东西
Last week we only had one scene in our game, which was just a play scene.
上周我们在比赛中只有一个场景 那只是一个游戏场景
And even though we had like a game over state within that scene,
即使我们在那个场景中有一场比赛
we didn't transition between scenes.
我们没有在场景之间过渡
We just sort of reloaded the same scene.
我们只是重新加载了同样的场景
Today we'll have a title screen and a play scene, which
今天我们将有一个标题屏幕和一个游戏场景 其中
is an evolution of the idea that we had in LOVE 2D
是我们在2D中相爱的想法的演变
where we had a state machine that was governing our entire game in terms
在那里我们有一个状态机 它统治着我们的整个游戏
of the different states that we could be in, whether it
我们可能所处的不同状态 无论是
was the title, the game over, the play state, and so forth.
是标题、游戏结束、播放状态等等
Unity does the same thing with scene objects, which are effectively
Unity对场景对象做了同样的事情 它是有效的
a snapshot of a series of game objects aligned
一系列对齐的游戏对象的快照
in a particular way in the editor.
在编辑器中以一种特定的方式
We'll talk about fog and also global lighting
我们将讨论雾和全局照明
and certain other things that allow us to create
以及某些其他东西 允许我们创造
a atmosphere conducive to the sort of feel
一种有利于那种感觉的氛围
that we want to get in our game today, which is sort of creepy and eerie.
我们今天想要进入我们的游戏 这是一种令人毛骨悚然和诡异的东西
And lastly, when we talk about how to create UI elements in the game,
最后 当我们谈论如何在游戏中创建UI元素时
we'll talk about Unity 2D, its canvas object, and text labels
我们将讨论Unity 2D 它的画布对象和文本标签
and some other things and how those all operate,
以及其他一些事情 以及它们是如何运作的
which is sort of two sides of the same coin.
这是一个硬币的两面
Unity 3D also comes bundled with Unity 2D,
Unity 3D还与Unity 2D捆绑在一起
a set of tools used to make not only 2D games but also 2D interfaces that you
一套工具 不仅用于制作2D游戏 还用于制作2D界面
can apply to your 3D games.
可以应用到您的3D游戏中
So first, a demo.
首先是demo
Now I've been sick for the last week, so I'm not
上周我一直在生病 所以我
going to ask for anybody to come up and demo just because I don't
我会要求任何人来演示 因为我不
want to get anybody else sick, so I'm going
我不想传染其他人所以我要去
to just go ahead and show, just this lecture, the game
在这节课上 我们来展示一下这个博弈
that I put together for you.
我为你准备的
So here I have two scenes.
这里有两个场景
Notice here I have a title scene and a place scene.
注意这里我有一个标题场景和一个地点场景
I'm in the Unity editor right now.
我现在在Unity编辑器中
I'm going to load up the title scene here, which I've done.
我将在这里加载标题场景 我已经完成了
And then notice that it has sort of a game view and a scene view.
然后注意它有一个游戏视图和一个场景视图
I'm going to hit play.
我要按播放键了
We're going to make sure that it's set to maximize, which it is.
我们要确保它被设置为最大化 它是
And so we have sound here, so we should hear audio.
所以我们这里有声音 所以我们应该听到音频
And hit play.
按播放键
And notice that we have sort of like this ambient creepy music track
请注意我们有一段背景音乐
playing.
玩了
We have a very-- we could have easily done this in LOVE 2D.
我们有一个非常-我们可以很容易地在爱情2D中做到这一点
This is just a black screen with two text labels on it.
这只是一个黑色的屏幕 上面有两个文本标签
And this is done with Unity's 2D UI toolkit.
这是通过Unity的2D UI工具包完成的
And so it says--
所以它说--
it tells us to press Enter.
它告诉我们按回车键
So if I press Enter, We instantly get teleported into like this maze,
所以如果我按下回车键 我们会立刻被传送到这个迷宫里
this creepy looking maze.
这个诡异的迷宫
And so I can walk around in this maze.
所以我可以在这个迷宫里走
And there are a few things going on.
有一些事情正在发生
So anybody-- can anybody tell me some of the things
有谁能告诉我
they notice about the scene, what jumps out at them?
他们注意到了这个场景 他们会注意到什么？
What are some of the elements?
有哪些要素？
If you were to put this together yourself, where would you start?
如果你要自己把这些放在一起 你会从哪里开始？
What are the pieces that we can put together here?
我们能把什么拼在一起？
Yes.
是的
Yep.
必须有一个你可以立足的地方 而且确实有
So we're generating not only walls in our scene, of course,
当然 我们在场景中生成的不仅仅是墙
but we need a ground to sit in.
但我们得找个地方坐下
And also if you look up top, it's kind of difficult to tell,
如果你往上看 很难分辨
but we also have a ceiling so ground and the ceiling and walls.
但我们也有一个天花板 所以地面 天花板和墙壁
Some kind of lighting.
某种照明
Yes.
是的
And so in this case, we're actually using ambient world
所以在这个例子中 我们实际上是在利用周围环境
lighting as opposed to having a light source.
照明 而不是有光源
So we'll take a look at that.
所以我们来看看
In last week's lecture, we used--
在上周的课上 我们用了
two weeks prior's lecture, we used a directional light object.
在两周前的讲座中 我们使用了一个定向光物体
But in this case, we have no lights in the scene.
但在这种情况下 场景中没有灯光
We're actually using Unity's world lighting,
我们实际上使用了Unity的世界照明
which we'll take a look at soon.
我们很快就会看到
When we walk around, notice that I can move where
当我们四处走动时 注意我可以移动到
my camera is looking with my mouse.
我的摄像头在用鼠标看
So we're actually controlling the camera with a first person controller, an FPS
所以我们实际上是用第一人称控制器来控制摄像机 FPS
controller, which is actually a component that Unity provides to you.
控制器 它实际上是Unity提供给你的一个组件
And then notice eventually if we keep exploring the maze,
然后注意到如果我们继续探索迷宫
we come across this little thing here, which is sort of a pickup.
我们在这里遇到了这个小东西 它是一种皮卡
And when we pick this up, we get like this weird creepy piano
当我们拿起这个的时候 我们就像一架奇怪的钢琴
sound and then the scene reloads.
声音 然后场景重新加载
Does anybody notice anything about what we see in the distance,
有没有人注意到我们在远处看到的东西
like how that's affected?
比如这是如何影响的
Like if I'm looking at this wall right here,
就像我看着这面墙
for example, it's kind of hard to tell, but as
比如说 这很难说
opposed to like down this hallway, what's the difference there?
而不是在这条走廊里有什么区别
AUDIENCE: The light source is further away, I guess.
观众：我想光源离得更远
COLTON OGDEN: The light source is further away.
科尔顿·奥格登：光源更远
Kind of.
算是吧
So what we're experiencing here-- we're seeing it's
所以我们现在看到的
a graphics sort of concept called fog.
一种叫做雾的图形概念
And so what fog lets you do is it effectively adds color
所以雾能让你有效地增加色彩
to the scene based upon how far away the objects are in the scene
基于对象在场景中的距离
and multiplies color onto them.
并将颜色添加到它们上
And it gives you the illusion of looking--
它给你一种错觉
as if you're surrounded by fog basically.
就好像你被雾包围了一样
And it's been around for a very long time, back even as far as the N64 days.
它已经存在了很长一段时间 甚至可以追溯到N64天
And we'll talk about that later today and it's actually incredibly easy
我们今天晚些时候会讲到 这其实非常简单
to add that into a game with Unity and its world lighting system.
将其添加到Unity游戏及其世界照明系统中
Any idea as to how fog, not only in terms of aesthetics,
有没有关于雾 不仅仅是美学上的
but how it could maybe help with performance?
但它如何可能有助于性能？
Yeah.
是啊
AUDIENCE: Don't need as much pixel clarity because it's already
观众：不需要太高的像素清晰度 因为它已经
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: You don't need as much pixel clarity.
你不需要那么多的像素清晰度
Kind of.
算是吧
The big thing about fog and the way that it was used a long time ago
很久以前人们对雾的使用
is that, because eventually things are completely
因为最终事情完全
opaque beyond a certain point, you don't need far draw distance in your game.
不透明超过一定的点 你不需要在你的游戏远提请距离
So you can actually like dynamically-- you
所以你实际上可以动态地喜欢--你
can omit rendering things that are a certain distance away
可以省略渲染一定距离以外的事物
because you wouldn't be able to see them anyway.
因为无论如何你都看不到他们
And so this was an optimization technique used a lot back
这是一种优化技术
when draw distance was a huge bottleneck on computers
当绘制距离是计算机的一个巨大瓶颈时
and game video game consoles back in the 90s for example.
和电子游戏机
Like Silent Hill, the game for PS1, was almost exclusively fog.
像寂静岭 PS1的游戏 几乎完全是雾
And you can see very little in front of you.
在你面前 你几乎看不到什么
And we'll see a screenshot of that later.
我们稍后会看到一个截图
And they use that to boost their performance
他们利用这一点来提高他们的表现
and also to provide a certain aesthetic.
并且还提供一定的美感
And then one other thing you might be paying attention to
还有一件事你可能会注意
is there's a sound on a loop, just sort of this creepy sort of whispering sound
就是有一个循环的声音 有点像是令人毛骨悚然的低语声
and that's to just add atmosphere.
这只是为了增加气氛
Right.
对的
Just because without it, we would-- it's little things like that, especially
只是因为没有它 我们会--这是这样的小事情 特别是
in horror games like this, the atmosphere can be everything.
在这样的恐怖游戏中 气氛可以决定一切
So with very simple ideas, fog, some whispers, first person controller,
用非常简单的想法 雾 一些耳语 第一人称控制器
so you have tight hallways, you can produce something that's pretty scary.
所以你有狭窄的走廊 你可以生产一些非常可怕的东西
Now there are a few things missing from this,
这里还缺少一些东西
namely there's nothing that's going to come at you and attack you.
也就是说 没有任何东西会攻击你
But it would be not terribly difficult to add,
但要加上一点也不难
but because we're using procedural generation,
但是因为我们使用的是程序生成
you would need what's called a nav mesh.
你需要一种所谓的导航网状物
And you would need to generate that procedurally so that things
你需要程序化地生成它 这样才能
could follow you in 3D space.
可以在3D空间里跟踪你
We might have some time to talk about how to do that a little bit
我们可能会有时间来讨论一下如何做到这一点
later today, but that's not implemented in this particular lecture.
今天晚些时候 但这并没有在这节课中实现
But it would be not too infeasible to accomplish.
但要做到这一点也不是太不可行
But those are some of the pieces that we'll take a look at today.
但这些是我们今天要看的一些片段
So this is the title scene.
这就是片名场景
Notice that there's not a whole lot here actually, so if I zoom back out,
请注意 实际上这里并不是很多 所以如果我缩小
we can see canvases are huge in Unity just
我们可以看到油画是巨大的 只是在单位
because it's more optimized for the engine to render them that way.
因为以这种方式呈现它们对引擎来说更加优化
But we can see, even though it's a 2D UI, it's very visible in 3D space.
但我们可以看到 尽管这是一个2D用户界面 但它在3D空间中非常明显
And if you click this button here, we end up getting--
如果你点击这里的按钮 我们最终会得到--
oh, no.
哦 不
That just brings us into-- sorry.
这只会让我们陷入--抱歉
Click this button here.
点击这里的按钮
That brings us into the 2D Unity 2D mode.
这将把我们带入2D Unity 2D模式
So now we're interacting with things in 2D.
因此 现在我们正在与2D中的事物进行交互
And I can actually click on this label and move it around
实际上 我可以点击这个标签并将其移动
in 2D as if we were using a 2D game engine as opposed to a 3D game engine.
在2D中 就好像我们使用的是2D游戏引擎 而不是3D游戏引擎
So we'll look at that a little bit later.
所以我们稍后会看到这一点
This is just the title scene.
这只是片名的场景
So the play scene itself--
所以这场戏本身--
I'm not going to save that.
我不会把它存起来的
The play scene itself--
话剧场景本身--
I'm going to go from 2D back to 3D here--
我将从2D回到3D--
is pretty much empty.
几乎是空的
So we have a first person controller here.
所以我们这里有一个第一人称控制人
This is the FPS controller object.
这是FPS控制器对象
Does anybody-- anybody tell what basically constitutes an FPS controller
有人--有人告诉我FPS控制器的基本构成吗？
just by looking at the scene here?
仅仅通过看这里的场景就可以了？
What are some of the pieces that jump out at you?
有哪些片段会让你眼前一亮？
AUDIENCE: I thought you just put the camera right where the player is
观众：我以为你只是把摄像机放在球员所在的地方
or right in front of the player.
或者就在球员面前
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
You put the camera right where the player is, effectively
你把相机放在玩家所在的地方 效果很好
where your head should be relative to where their body is.
你的头应该相对于他们身体的位置
And their body-- what's constituting their body here?
他们的身体--他们的身体是由什么构成的？
Can you tell?
你能看出来吗？
AUDIENCE: It could just be a-- it looks like a cube in the middle there.
观众：它可能只是一个--它看起来像一个中间的立方体
COLTON OGDEN: It's actually this capsule right here.
科尔顿·奥格登：实际上就是这个太空舱
I don't know if you can see it.
我不知道你能不能看出来
There's this capsule here, this green capsule.
这里有一个胶囊 这个绿色的胶囊
It's a little bit more organic feeling than a cube necessarily,
它一定比立方体更有组织的感觉
but you could use a cube as well.
但你也可以用一个立方体
But a capsule is how character controllers in Unity are represented.
但在Unity中 角色控制器是用胶囊表示的
And character controllers come for free in Unity, which is really nice.
而角色控制器在Unity中是免费的 这真的很好
They're part of the standard assets.
它们是标准资产的一部分
So if you go to import package, in Unity--
因此 如果您要导入包 在Unity中--
if you go into Assets, Import Package, there's
如果您进入资产、导入包 则会有
a lot of packages that come for free that sort of bootstrap you.
很多免费提供的套餐都会给你带来些许帮助
Notice there's like 2D packages, the cameras, characters.
请注意 里面有2D套装、摄像机、角色
The characters package has 3D characters or third person characters,
角色包具有3D角色或第三人称角色
first person characters, some that are physics based,
第一人称角色 有些是基于物理的
some that are not physics based.
有些不是基于物理的
This particular controller is not physics
这个特殊的控制器不是物理控制器
based, meaning that we don't apply forces to it.
基于 这意味着我们不会对其施加力量
We move it around.
我们把它搬来搬去
It's kinematic.
它是运动学的
It is affected by gravity, so in a sense it kind of is physics based,
它受到重力的影响 所以从某种意义上说 它是基于物理的
but it's not strictly physics based like a rigid body and a rigid body would.
但它不像刚体和刚体那样严格地基于物理
And the collisions that occur between this and another rigid body
以及发生在这个刚体和另一个刚体之间的碰撞
aren't the same as they would be if we were
不同于如果我们是的话
to make this a purely rigid body based character controller.
以使其成为纯粹基于刚体的角色控制器
There is a purely rigid body based character controller
有一个纯粹基于刚体的角色控制器
that you can import-- haven't experimented with it a lot,
你可以进口的--还没有做过很多试验
but you could probably figure out a good use for that in terms of a game
但你可能会想出这在游戏中有很好的用途
or maybe you want to move precisely on surfaces that have different materials,
或者 您可能想要在具有不同材质的表面上精确移动
like icy surfaces or whatnot, and have it apply it
喜欢结冰的表面或诸如此类的东西 并让它应用
in a very physically realistic way.
以一种非常现实的方式
And a few things that we have here in our play scene--
在我们的游戏场景中 我们有一些东西--
we have a dungeon generator object.
我们有一个地牢发电机物体
So this dungeon generator object is just an empty object
所以这个地下城生成器对象只是一个空对象
with a level generator script here.
这里有一个电平生成器脚本
And then we have a few other objects, a floor parent, a walls parent,
然后我们还有其他几个对象 地板父对象 墙父对象
and a whisper source.
还有一个耳语来源
So we'll get into the details of what all of those mean.
因此 我们将深入了解所有这些内容的具体含义
Our goal today will be talking about a few things.
我们今天的目标是谈论几件事
So we'll be talking about-- here's a picture of just our maze.
所以我们将讨论--这是一张我们迷宫的照片
So we talked about some of those things at a high level.
因此 我们在高级别上讨论了其中一些事情
We'll actually explore how to implement them in Unity today, so making a maze,
今天我们将探索如何在Unity中实现它们 所以做一个迷宫
making the fog effect, walking through it with our character controller.
制作雾效果 用我们的角色控制器穿行
We want to be able to have some kind of game play here,
我们希望能够在这里进行某种游戏
so we have collectibles in the form of this red coin.
所以我们有这种红色硬币形式的收藏品
This is actually part of another standard assets pack, the prototype
这实际上是另一个标准资产包的一部分 即原型
assets pack.
资产打包
It comes with a prototype little coin object that you can throw in.
它附带了一个原型小硬币物体 你可以扔进去
Anybody notice anything about this coin beyond the fact
有没有人注意到这枚硬币有什么特别之处
that it's just a red coin?
这只是一枚红色硬币？
What else do you know it's about this scene here?
你还知道这一幕还有什么原因吗？
AUDIENCE: It's emitting a glow.
观众：它在发光
COLTON OGDEN: It's emitting a glow.
科尔顿·奥格登：它在发光
Any ideas as to how it's emitting a glow?
关于它是如何发光的有什么想法吗？
AUDIENCE: There's a light source inside of it?
观众：里面有光源吗？
COLTON OGDEN: There's a light source inside of it.
科尔顿·奥格登：里面有一个光源
Exactly.
一点儿没错
So we'll talk about that.
所以我们会讨论这个问题
We'll show you how that's implemented.
我们将向您展示如何实现这一点
Very easy to do in Unity.
在Unity中很容易做到
And then we'll also talk about, towards the end, our 2D scene, our title scene,
然后我们还将在最后讨论我们的2D场景 我们的标题场景
and how to construct it, which is actually very easy in Unity
以及如何构建它 这在Unity中实际上非常容易
as opposed to doing something by code.
而不是通过代码来做某事
You very rarely actually for interfaces need to touch
你很少真正需要触摸界面
code, at least in terms of how to lay them out.
代码 至少在如何布局它们方面是这样
In Unity you can do everything very visually and with the mouse.
在Unity中 您可以非常直观地使用鼠标做任何事情
Actually, it's a pleasure to make interfaces
事实上 制作界面是一件很愉快的事情
if you're used to just making them in code.
如果您习惯于只用代码编写它们的话
So texturing-- so last week or two weeks ago, we did nothing with textures.
所以纹理--所以上周或两周前 我们没有做任何纹理方面的工作
Well, that's not true.
好吧 那不是真的
We had one texture on the background, which
我们在背景上有一个纹理 它
was the sort of scrolling background.
是一种滚动的背景
But we didn't really look at that too much.
但我们并没有太多地关注这一点
In today's example, you know the helicopter and the coin
在今天的例子中 你知道直升机和硬币
and the buildings and all that stuff, those
还有那些建筑和所有的东西 那些
were all just polygons with flat colors associated with them.
都是与平面颜色相关联的多边形
Today we'll be talking about how to actually texture things with materials.
今天我们将讨论如何使用材质对物体进行纹理处理
And so this is very easy to do in Unity.
因此 在Unity中很容易做到这一点
So I'm going to go over to my title scene
所以我要去我的片名现场
here, just because it's lit in a fairly normal way as opposed to the play
在这里 仅仅因为它是以一种与剧本相反的相当正常的方式点亮的
scene, which is not lit in a normal way because we're
场景 它不是以正常方式照明的 因为我们
using environment lighting.
使用环境照明
We don't have a sky box.
我们没有天空盒子
The title scene has a fairly normal lighting set up.
标题场景具有相当正常的照明设置
So if I add a cube here to the scene, you
因此 如果我在场景中添加一个立方体 您可以
can see right off the bat by default we do get a material here,
可以立即看到默认情况下我们确实在这里得到了一份材料
which has what's called an albedo component.
它有一种叫做反照率的成分
Albedo just means like what's its surface color look like.
反照率只是指它的表面颜色是什么样子的
It has a much more technical definition.
它有一个更技术性的定义
And you can look up on Wikipedia what albedo means.
你可以在维基百科上查到什么是反照率
It has something to do with the way that light interacts with surfaces.
这与光与表面相互作用的方式有关
There's a lot of other elements here.
这里还有很多其他的元素
You can make something look metallic.
你可以让东西看起来像金属
You can make it look smooth or rough.
你可以让它看起来光滑或粗糙
And you can also add normal maps, height maps,
您还可以添加法线贴图、高度贴图、
and a few other things, which gives it more of like a bumpy texture,
还有一些其他的东西 这让它更像是凹凸不平的质地
and so forth.
以此类推
And you can also make things emit light this way,
你也可以用这种方式让物体发光
which the coin actually not only emits light but also is a light source.
这枚硬币实际上不仅发光 而且还是一个光源
So it does both.
因此 它同时做到了这两点
And there's a few other things here.
这里还有一些其他的东西
For example, let's say you have a very large cube and a small texture.
例如 假设你有一个非常大的立方体和一个很小的纹理
If you put a very small texture on a large cube,
如果你把一个非常小的纹理放在一个大立方体上
what's it going to look like?
它会是什么样子的？
What's your instinct?
你的直觉是什么？
What if we have a very large cube, but a very-- like
如果我们有一个非常大的立方体 但一个非常--就像
say we have a 64 by 64 pixel texture, but our cube is humongous?
假设我们有一个64x64像素的纹理 但我们的立方体是巨大的吗？
What effect is that going to have on the cube?
这会对立方体产生什么影响？
It's going to look kind of like an N64 cube, right?
它看起来会有点像N64立方体 对吗？
What basically happens is it's going to interpolate between the texture
基本上发生的是它将在纹理之间进行内插
pixels, the texels when you apply a texture to your cube.
像素 即将纹理应用于立方体时的纹理元素
And so when you apply a small texture to a large surface,
因此 当你将一个小纹理应用到一个大表面上时
it's going to look stretched.
它会看起来被拉长了
It's going to look also filtered as like you sort of see in some YouTube videos
它看起来也会经过过滤 就像你在YouTube视频中看到的那样
if you watch them and they're recorded a very small resolution,
如果你观看它们 它们被记录在一个非常小的分辨率上
but you blow them up.
但你却把它们炸飞了
They look filtered or if you've ever stretched
它们看起来像是过滤过的 或者如果你曾经伸展过
a picture in the right software and it looks interpolated in a filter,
一张图片放在正确的软件中 在滤镜中看起来像是内插的
it's going to have that look.
它会有那样的样子
So what you can do is you can apply tiling.
所以你能做的就是贴瓷砖
So here we can see there's a tiling element x and y.
所以在这里我们可以看到 有一个平铺元素x和y
So a one in the x and y direction, because it only
所以在x和y方向上是1 因为它只
applies on a flat surface.
适用于平面
So the effect of tiling would be such that if you have a 64 by 64 texture,
所以平铺的效果是这样的 如果你有一个64x64的纹理
you could just tile that texture several times to get the desired
您只需将该纹理平铺几次即可获得所需的效果
look that you want on whatever surface that you're
看着你想要的任何表面 你是
trying to look at in your game world.
试着在你的游戏世界里看
Maybe it's a very small object or maybe it's a very large object
可能是一个非常小的物体 也可能是一个非常大的物体
that you're looking at as a character and you want
你作为一个角色来看待你想要的
to tile bricks for example or stone.
例如 瓦砖或石头
So to apply a texture to a 3D object in the scene, I'm going to go into here.
因此 为了将纹理应用到场景中的3D对象 我将进入这里
So you need a material first.
所以你首先需要一种材料
And so these are all Unity material objects.
这些都是Unity材质对象
You can tell because they have a circular--
你可以看出来 因为他们有一个圆形--
they all look like as if they've been wrapped around a sphere.
它们看起来都像是被包裹在一个球体上
These are all Unity materials as opposed to textures.
这些都是Unity材质 而不是纹理
Textures are just 2D objects, 2D textures, 2D images.
纹理只是2D对象、2D纹理、2D图像
So this is part of an asset pack that I downloaded
这是我下载的资产包的一部分
for this lecture called low poly dungeon modules, which is in the asset store.
这节课的题目是低聚地下城模块 它在资产商店里
And so what I'm going to do is I'm going to apply--
所以我要做的就是申请--
let's say I want to just apply this rock material to this object.
假设我只想将此岩石材质应用于此对象
Right.
正确的
Then I go over to that.
然后我就去找那个
I'm going to first add a--
我要先加一个--
I think because I went into the material it had a incorrect appearance.
我想是因为我进入了材料中 所以它的外观不正确
So do that.
那就这么做吧
Oh, that's strange.
哦 那太奇怪了
I'm going to create a new scene.
我要创造一个新的场景
And then I'm going to add a cube and then a--
然后我要添加一个立方体 然后--
not pop but maybe the beam.
不是爆裂 可能是横梁
I wonder why it is not--
我想知道为什么不是--
that's very strange.
这太奇怪了
For some reason, it might be a setting that I
出于某种原因 这可能是我
have enabled that's not allowing it to correctly render.
已经启用了不允许其正确渲染的功能
But the effect of that should be that we apply-- normally
但这样做的效果应该是我们通常会应用
if you apply a texture to a material, it'll
如果将纹理应用于材质 它将
have the effect of creating-- it'll instantly texture it.
有创造的效果--它会立即产生纹理
But what I can do is I can go to textures here.
但我能做的是 我可以在这里转到纹理
And this should work too.
这也应该是可行的
I can go to that and then it'll apply it that way.
我可以转到那里 然后它就会这样应用它
So normally, if you're in a fresh project and you add a new 3D object,
因此 通常情况下 如果你在一个新的项目中添加了一个新的3D对象
and you just click and drag a material onto a 3D object,
你只需点击一种材质并将其拖到3D对象上
it will texture it for you.
它会为你带来质感
In this case, I think because it's automatically
在这种情况下 我认为因为它自动地
assigning a material to these objects based on some project setting
基于某些项目设置将材质指定给这些对象
that I off the cuff just unable to--
我就是不能--
I don't know for sure--
我不确定--
you can instead just go to the albedo component here.
你可以转到这里的反照率分量
So albedo functions not only as a color but also as a texture for your object.
因此 反照率不仅是一种颜色 也是一种物体的纹理
And so you can apply a texture, just a 2D image,
所以你可以应用纹理 只需2D图像
to your albedo component of a material.
一种材料的反照率成分
Right.
正确的
And that will have the same effect as texturing it immediately.
这将具有与立即对其进行纹理处理相同的效果
So normally what this is supposed to do is create a albedo--
所以通常情况下 这应该会产生一个反照率--
create a new material with that texture as the albedo when
创建具有该纹理作为反照率的新材质
you set a material to the 3D object.
您可以为3D对象设置材质
Now I wonder if I--
现在我在想我是不是
Yeah.
嗯
I'm not sure.
我没有把握
I'm not sure exactly why it didn't work like right off the bat
我不太清楚为什么它不能立刻起作用
like it's normally supposed to.
就像它通常应该做的那样
In a fresh project, it will.
在一个全新的项目中 它会的
I'll try to investigate.
我会试着去调查
But if it ever happens like that where for some reason you're--
但如果发生这样的事情 出于某种原因 你会--
I think it has to do with the way the shaders are set on here.
我认为这与着色器设置在这里的方式有关
Maybe there's a setting I'm just not sure about.
也许有一种背景我只是不太确定
But you can just set the albedo component here manually.
但您可以在此处手动设置反照率分量
It'll have the same effect.
它也会有同样的效果
So the albedo component of your material, setting that with a texture,
所以你材料的反照率成分 设置了一种纹理
textures objects.
为对象添加纹理
And so that's effectively how we get from this sort of look
所以这就是我们从这种外观中得到的有效方式
of a flat shaded or flat color shaded object to a texture shaded
从平面着色或平面颜色着色对象到纹理着色
object just like that.
就像这样的物体
And texture mapping in itself is a very wide field and fairly complicated,
而纹理贴图本身就是一个非常广泛的领域 而且相当复杂
but ultimately it looks something like this.
但最终它看起来像这样
So does anybody-- can anybody tell me what this looks like here?
有谁能告诉我这是什么样子的吗？
So we see here obviously we have a fully textured model.
所以我们在这里看到 很明显 我们有一个完全纹理的模型
But if we're looking at this, what does it look like we've done here?
但如果我们看这个 我们看起来像是做了什么？
So what does it look like?
那么它看起来是什么样子呢？
Ignore all the lines.
忽略所有行
But what does it sort of look we have on the surface?
但我们在表面上看到的是什么样子呢？
It's just a texture, right?
这只是一种质感 对吧？
Oops.
哎呀
We can sort of see the colors here.
我们可以在这里看到一些颜色
For example, maybe his belt here or actually that
例如 也许他的腰带在这里或实际上是在那里
looks like the top of his head here.
看起来像是他的头顶
This being the top of his head, and then we have like his belt and other things.
这是他的头顶 然后我们有他的腰带和其他东西
This right here, we can pretty clearly see that's like sort of his face mask,
就在这里 我们可以很清楚地看到这就像是他的口罩
right?
对吗？
But it's just on a 2D surface, like this is a regular texture.
但它只是在2D表面上 就像这是一个规则的纹理
And so what we've done here is basically taken
所以我们在这里所做的基本上是
all of the polygons that comprise the model and laid them out flat, right?
组成模型的所有多边形 并将它们平铺 对吗？
Lay them out flat as if on a table where our texture is
把它们平放在我们的纹理所在的桌子上
and that's what UV mapping is.
这就是UV贴图的含义
And this is usually something that you do in whatever 3D modeling software
这通常是你在任何3D建模软件中都要做的事情
that you're using.
你正在使用的东西
In Unity, when you apply a texture to a material, or a material with a texture
在Unity中 将纹理应用于材质或具有纹理的材质时
to an object, it will use its standard--
对于一个物体 它将使用它的标准--
it has its own built in mapping algorithm
它有自己的内置映射算法
that will apply material to a model.
这将对模型应用材质
And so it does it differently for different objects.
因此 它对不同的对象做了不同的处理
We can create like a sphere for example.
例如 我们可以像球体一样创建
Move the sphere over here.
把球体移到这里来
And I'm going to try again and just to see if applying the material
我会再试一次 看看是否将这种材料
works on that.
对此很感兴趣
No.
不是的
It doesn't.
这是不可能的
So applying a-- so if we go into this material
所以应用一种--所以如果我们进入这个材料
here, which is, for some reason, grayed out.
这里 由于某种原因 它是灰色的
New scene again.
又是新场景
Create a new 3D sphere.
创建新的3D球体
And then oh, this time it looks like it's-- oh, I can't tell.
然后 哦 这一次看起来像是--哦 我不知道
No.
不是的
I don't think that's working.
我不认为这有什么用
Oh.
噢
Now it allows us to accept a texture.
现在它允许我们接受一种纹理
OK.
好的
So we can apply a texture.
这样我们就可以应用纹理了
Whoops.
哎呦
Can apply a texture to that.
可以对其应用纹理
And so now we can see our sphere has been mapped as well.
所以现在我们可以看到我们的球体也被映射了
And it looks fairly convincing.
而且它看起来相当令人信服
It's been wrapped around in a way that it doesn't
它被包裹在一种它不会
look too distorted or too weird.
看起来太扭曲或太奇怪了
And so Unity has its own ways of mapping for its primitive objects,
因此 Unity有自己的原始对象贴图方式
whether it's spheres, cubes, we have a few other ones, capsules, cylinders,
无论是球体 立方体 我们还有其他一些 胶囊 圆柱体
planes.
飞机
It'll depend, obviously, on what your texture is.
显然 这取决于你的质地是什么
If your texture is fairly ornate, it might end up looking distorted.
如果您的纹理相当华丽 它最终可能会看起来扭曲
But for most purposes, for simple primitive objects, for most textures
但对于大多数目的 对于简单的基本体对象 对于大多数纹理
it should work pretty well.
它应该运行得很好
Now if you imported a model that was like a table or a character
现在 如果您导入了一个类似于桌子或角色的模型
and you just applied a texture to it, it's not going to look good.
而你刚刚给它涂上了纹理 它看起来不会很好
It's going to look messed up.
它会看起来一团糟
And so your 3D software will export a material
因此 您的3D软件将导出一种材质
with the model assuming that you've modeled
该模型假定您已对
in that software with a texture.
在那个有质感的软件里
It'll actually give you a material that you can then
它实际上会给你一种材料 然后你就可以
reference that will properly apply a texture to your character,
将适当地将纹理应用于角色的引用
but the same sort of apply a texture, just
但同样的一种应用纹理 只是
a regular texture to a complicated model,
复杂模型的规则纹理
just isn't going to work because it hasn't been UV mapped in a smart way.
只是不起作用 因为它没有以一种智能的方式进行UV贴图
Unity's not going to know I have a table.
Unity不会知道我有桌子的
I want to map the texture to the table in a way that looks convincing.
我想以一种看起来令人信服的方式将纹理映射到桌子上
You can see this kind of if we create a cube.
如果我们创建一个立方体 你可以看到这种情况
And then if we go ahead and--
然后如果我们继续--
been making apparent for some reason.
因为某些原因而变得明显起来
If we go up here, I'm going to first assign--
如果我们从这里上去 我要先分配--
OK.
好的
For some reason that worked instantly.
出于某种原因 这种做法立即奏效了
But you can see we've applied a sort of wall texture to it.
但你可以看到 我们对它应用了一种墙体纹理
And then if we scale it down-- so this is the scale button up here.
如果我们按比例缩小--这是上面的比例按钮
You can move, rotate things.
你可以移动、旋转东西
If unfamiliar, these top buttons up here are transform operators.
如果不熟悉 这里上面的这些顶部按钮是变换操作符
So you can move things, rotate things, and scale things.
这样你就可以移动物体、旋转物体和缩放物体
So if you scale this along this y-axis a bit and then you zoom in,
所以如果你沿着这个y轴缩放一点 然后你放大
the texture looks pretty compressed and distorted,
纹理看起来非常压缩和扭曲
because it's just doing the same algorithm
因为它只是在做同样的算法
and assuming it's the same kind of surface
假设它是相同类型的表面
without taking into consideration how it's been warped.
而不考虑它是如何被扭曲的
Right.
正确的
So ideally you wouldn't have this flattening happening.
因此 理想情况下 你不会让这种扁平化发生
And so in your 3D software, you would unwrap your model
因此 在您的3D软件中 您可以打开模型
and then apply a texture to each separate polygon of your model
然后将纹理应用到模型的每个单独的多边形
in a way that looks convincing.
以一种看起来令人信服的方式
And so this isn't anything that you necessarily
所以这不是你必须要做的事情
have to do for the lectures, or for the demonstration for your project.
为你的项目做讲课或演示
But if you are creating your own 3D assets, if you're importing 3D assets,
但是 如果您正在创建自己的3D资源 如果您正在导入3D资源
and if you want to use textures in a way that we're doing today,
如果你想以我们今天所做的方式使用纹理
you will need to probably become familiar with UV wrapping, UV
您可能需要熟悉UV包装 UV
unwrapping, UV mapping in whatever software that you're using.
在您正在使用的任何软件中展开、UV贴图
And if you're just unfamiliar with it in general
如果你只是总体上不熟悉它
and have wanted to know what goes on in turning a flat white polygon
并想知道在将一个平坦的白色多边形
character into something that has a texture,
角色变成了有质感的东西
this is effectively what happens.
这实际上就是发生的事情
You unwrap it, make it flat, sort of like stamp
你打开它 把它压平 有点像邮票
the material onto it effectively, and that maps the UVs of the texture,
有效地将材质映射到其上 并映射纹理的UV
so the texture's virtual coordinates to your 3D model.
因此纹理的虚拟坐标指向您的3D模型
So any questions as to how this works at all
所以有没有任何关于这是如何运作的问题
or about unity and applying textures?
或者关于统一和应用纹理？
AUDIENCE: What's the general way that you make the textures on the right
观众：你们制作右侧纹理的一般方法是什么
where it's like a world that's been flattened?
就像是一个被夷为平地的世界？
COLTON OGDEN: How do you make the textures on the right?
科尔顿·奥格登：你如何制作右边的纹理？
I mean that's kind of an art form in itself.
我的意思是 这本身就是一种艺术形式
You do have to do it by hand and know--
你确实需要用手来做 而且你知道--
I mean, there's a good amount of trial and error
我是说 有大量的试验和错误
that will go into it, too, as you're making your model
这一点也会出现在你制作模型的过程中
and unwrapping it and noticing, oh, this looks weird,
打开它 注意到 哦 这看起来很奇怪
as I am applying this polygon to the surface.
当我将这个多边形应用到曲面上时
I'm going to go ahead and change that texture.
我将继续更改这种纹理
But you could use any-- you could use Gimp or Photoshop or any standard
但你可以使用任何--你可以使用Gimp或Photoshop或任何标准
texture creation software and just--
纹理创建软件和Just--
it's something-- I don't do a lot of it, but it's something
这是一种东西--我不经常做 但它是一种
that I imagine that you just get better at with time.
我想你会随着时间的推移变得更好
And texture artists and modeling artists probably develop sort of like
纹理艺术家和造型艺术家可能会开发出类似于
an attuned sense of what makes a good texture versus what doesn't.
对什么是好的纹理 什么是不好的有一个协调的感觉
Generally, you'll make the model first and then you'll make the texture.
通常 您将首先制作模型 然后再制作纹理
OK.
好的
So we already talked a little bit about models--
所以我们已经谈了一些模特的事情--
sorry, about materials.
抱歉 关于材料的事
We'll go back over it really briefly again.
我们会非常简短地再回顾一遍
There is a resource that I really like and I
有一个我非常喜欢的资源 我
think does a really wonderful job of teaching far
Think在教学方面做得非常好
beyond the basics of Unity.
超越了团结的基础
And that's catlikecoding.com, and it's totally free.
这就是Catlikecoding.com 它是完全免费的
They just have a bunch of free articles on there which are very in-depth.
他们只是在那里有一堆免费的文章 非常深入
And this is a screen shot taken from one of the articles
这是其中一篇文章的屏幕截图
where they talk about how to make really interesting materials.
在那里他们谈论如何制作真正有趣的材料
So you can see here, this one of the left,
所以你可以看到这里 左边的这一张
it looks very-- you know, it looks like a fireball,
它看起来非常--你知道 它看起来像一个火球
like it's made out of magma.
就像它是由岩浆制成的
And it's got bumps on it.
上面有凹凸不平的地方
It has contour you can see that there's sort of like a glow to the fire on it.
它有轮廓 你可以看到它上面有一种火焰的光芒
On the right, you can see that this model
在右边 你可以看到这个模型
has sort of conditional shine on certain parts of it.
有条件地照亮了它的某些部分
Like the metal part of it is shiny but the rest of it isn't.
就像它的金属部分是闪闪发光的 但它的其余部分却不是
And so how do we make certain parts of the material shiny?
那么 我们如何让这种材料的某些部分闪闪发光呢？
How do we make certain parts of it flat?
我们如何让它的某些部分变平呢？
The article goes in depth on that.
这篇文章对此进行了深入的探讨
Effectively what they do is they use several layers of maps,
实际上 他们所做的就是使用几层地图
like a shininess map, which is a texture that tells you--
比如光泽度贴图 这是一种纹理 它告诉你--
that you reference in a Unity custom shader that you write,
在您编写的Unity自定义着色器中引用的
which the article teaches you how to write.
这篇文章教你怎么写
Which will make certain parts of the texture glossy and certain parts
这将使纹理的某些部分和某些部分具有光泽
of it not glossy, so matte.
它没有光泽 所以没有光泽
And so you can do a lot of really cool, very interesting things,
所以你可以做很多非常酷、非常有趣的事情
and Unity's shading system is very--
而Unity的遮阳系统非常--
sort of the sky is the limit.
某种程度上说 天空是极限
Because it's effectively a standard shader language like you would--
因为它实际上是一种标准的着色器语言 就像你会--
it's effectively the same thing as HLSL, I believe,
我认为 这实际上与HLSL是一样的
which is High Level Shading Language which is a--
这是高级着色语言 这是一种--
if I'm not misremembering--
如果我没记错的话
Microsoft originally came up with it, and it's
它最初是由微软提出的 而且它是
very similar to GLSL, which is the open GL shading language.
非常类似于开放GL着色语言GLSL
And so what these are, effectively, is just little programs
因此 这些实际上只是一些小程序
that run on your graphics card.
在你的显卡上运行
We talked about this before.
我们以前谈过这个问题
But they tell your scene how to process lighting
但它们告诉您的场景如何处理灯光
for the objects that are within it.
对于其中的对象
And everything in Unity has a shader associated with it,
Unity中的所有东西都有一个与之相关联的着色器
even if it's just the standard shader, which by default is just a white color.
即使它只是标准着色器 默认情况下只是白色
But you can write your own shaders and you're
但您可以编写自己的着色器 并且
capable of virtually unlimited possibility.
具有几乎无限的可能性
And this effectively is all a shader, and it's all a shader
这实际上是一个着色器 它是一个着色器
that's been written in code.
这是用代码写的
But we have a lot of these variables that are exposed to us,
但我们有很多这样的变量暴露在我们面前
and albedo is one of them.
反照率就是其中之一
And albedo is sort of conditional.
反照率是有条件的
If it gets a texture applied to it, it will just render that texture.
如果它将纹理应用到它 它将只渲染该纹理
But if you apply color to it, it will apply that color to your material.
但如果您对其应用颜色 它会将该颜色应用于您的材质
And so that's how you can get, you know, textured
这就是你可以得到 你知道的 纹理
things versus non-textured things.
物件与非质感的物件
Metallic just computes shininess and reflectivity off of surfaces.
金属只计算曲面的光泽度和反射率
And that's just something that's written into the shader
这只是一些写入着色器的东西
and produces the lighting responsible to make that happen.
并产生负责实现这一目标的照明
And all of these different things are just part of a single shader.
所有这些不同的东西都只是一个着色器的一部分
And a material is effectively a shader.
材质实际上是着色器
They're kind of one in the same.
他们在某种程度上是同一个人
A material is a little bit different in that
材料在这一点上有点不同
you can also specify how its surface should interact with other things.
您还可以指定其曲面应如何与其他对象交互
So for example, if you're in an ice level,
举个例子 如果你在冰层上
a material can not only be like the sort of glossy, icy look of something,
一种材料不仅可以看起来像某种东西的光滑、冰冷的外观
but also, how slippery is it when I walk over it?
但是 当我走过它的时候 它有多滑？
And should I slide?
我应该滑行吗？
And how should other things interact with it that have physics?
还有其他有物理意义的东西应该如何与之相互作用呢？
So those two hand-in-hand are sort of what a material is.
因此 这两个手拉手是某种程度上的材料
But likely, as you're starting out the only real things
但很有可能 因为你开始做的唯一真正的事情
that you'll need to consider--
你需要考虑的是--
and you're sort of bound only by your curiosity--
而你只是受到好奇心的束缚--
our albedo and maybe metallic, and maybe emission.
我们的反照率 可能是金属的 也可能是排放物
And then depending on how much you-- how big your thing is
然后取决于你有多大--你的东西有多大
and how small your texture is, maybe tiling.
以及你的纹理有多小 可能是瓷砖
And then recall last week we manipulated offset.
然后回想起上周我们操纵了抵消
So offset is how much the texture is shifted, and recall it
所以偏移量是纹理移动的程度 并调用它
loops around back to the other side.
绕回另一边
And so by manipulating offset on the x-axis,
因此通过操纵x轴上的偏移量
we were able to get an infinitely scrolling texture, right?
我们能够得到无限滚动的纹理 对吗？
And so all of these things have their uses.
所以所有这些东西都有它们的用处
And pretty much everything in Unity has its uses.
而且 Unity中的几乎所有东西都有其用途
It's a very vast toolkit to use.
这是一个可以使用的非常庞大的工具包
But those are probably the important things that you'll see.
但这些可能是你将会看到的重要东西
And this article and many others on this website,
这篇文章和这个网站上的许多其他文章
which I highly recommend if you're looking to get really deep into Unity,
如果你想深入了解Unity 我强烈推荐这本书
will give you a lot of insight into how things work far beyond just the surface
将使您深入了解事物是如何工作的 而不仅仅是表面
level there.
拉平那里
So any questions on materials?
有什么关于材料的问题吗？
All right.
好的
So we're going take a look now at lighting.
所以我们现在来看看照明
So materials are one part of the equation.
所以材料是方程式的一部分
So that sort of defines how things should look when light hits them,
因此 这在某种程度上定义了物体在光线照射时应该是什么样子
but we also need light itself in our scene to illuminate things.
但我们也需要场景中的光本身来照亮事物
And so this is taken from another article on Catlike Coding on rendering.
这是摘自另一篇关于渲染的类似猫的编码的文章
And so this is a scene with a lot of lights, a lot
所以这是一个有很多灯光的场景 很多
of glowing lights, emissive lights.
发光的灯光 发光的灯光
And there's a lot more going on here, but this
还有很多事情要做 但这件事
is another great series of articles on how to understand the lighting
是关于如何理解照明的另一个很棒的系列文章
model in Unity.
统一中的模特
And it teaches you a lot.
它教会了你很多东西
It teaches you almost down to the very bare ingredients of the,
它几乎教会了你最基本的成分
sort of, the software and the rendering, if you want to go that deep.
某种程度上 软件和渲染 如果你想深入了解的话
I certainly haven't gone through every article
我当然没有看过每一篇文章
because there's a tremendous amount of content and it's very deep.
因为有大量的内容 而且非常深刻
But if you're looking to really get a sense of how it works,
但如果你想真正了解它是如何工作的
I would encourage you to explore that.
我鼓励你去探索这一点
So we'll look at a few different types of lighting.
因此 我们将介绍几种不同类型的照明
Beyond the more complicated things that this article talks about,
除了本文讨论的更复杂的事情之外
we'll look at the different styles of lights, which you'll probably
我们将介绍不同样式的灯光 您可能会看到
use more often as you're starting out.
当你刚开始的时候 要经常使用
So point lights.
所以点光源
Anybody have an idea as to what a point light might be based on this picture?
有谁知道基于这张图片的点光源可能是什么？
AUDIENCE: Pointing in a very specific direction?
观众：指的是一个非常具体的方向？
COLTON OGDEN: It's not pointing in a very specific direction.
科尔顿·奥格登：它并没有指向一个非常具体的方向
That's actually a spotlight.
这实际上是一个聚光灯
So a point light is a source of light that actually shoots out
因此 点光源是一种实际射出的光源
in all directions around it.
在它周围的各个方向
So it emits light in all directions, but within a confined area,
因此 它向各个方向发光 但在一个有限的区域内
at a specific intensity.
在特定的强度下
A spotlight shines light in a specific direction.
聚光灯向特定方向照射灯光
So only one direction.
所以只有一个方向
And what's interesting about spotlights is you can actually
聚光灯的有趣之处在于 你实际上可以
apply what's called a cookie to them.
给他们贴上所谓的曲奇
And what a cookie does, very similar to what the Batman light does,
曲奇的作用 非常类似于蝙蝠侠之光的作用
it allows you to apply a texture to a light
它允许您将纹理应用于灯光
and therefore cast shadows, specific shadows, on the light.
因此投射阴影 特定的阴影 在光上
So if you wanted to make something like the bat signal,
因此 如果你想制作类似蝙蝠信号的东西
you could put the Batman icon cookie on your spotlight.
你可以把蝙蝠侠图标饼干放在聚光灯下
And that will shine a light, but the Batman logo
这将会带来光明 但蝙蝠侠的标志
will be in the middle of it.
都会在这件事的中间
It's effectively the same thing as taking a literal spotlight
这实际上就是拿着一个字面意思的聚光灯
and putting a object onto it.
然后把一个物体放在上面
It produces a shadow.
它会产生阴影
A manual shadow.
手动阴影
AUDIENCE: It's called a cookie?
观众：这叫曲奇吗？
COLTON OGDEN: It's called a cookie, yep.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 这叫曲奇
A directional light.
平行光
Does anybody know what a directional light is?
有人知道平行光是什么吗？
So despite its name, it's actually not the same thing as a spotlight.
因此 尽管它的名字叫它 但实际上它与聚光灯不是一回事
So directional light-- we used a directional light last week, actually.
所以平行光--实际上 我们上周用的是平行光
Last lecture.
最后一堂课
Directional light casts light in a single direction,
平行光向单一方向投射光线
but throughout the entire scene, as if it's the sun.
但在整个场景中 就像是太阳一样
So this allows us to illuminate globally the entire scene,
因此 这使我们能够整体照亮整个场景
but all light gets cast from one direction.
但所有的光都是从一个方向投射的
So if you want to produce the appearance of daylight in your scene,
因此 如果要在场景中产生日光的外观
just a single directional light will illuminate everything.
只需一盏平行光就能照亮一切
And then the last thing, which is used less, is called an area light.
然后 最后一种使用较少的东西被称为区域光
So does anybody know-- can anybody guess what an area
那么有没有人知道--有没有人能猜出
light is based on this picture here?
光线是基于这张照片的吗？
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: It's light that's only on the surface?
观众：只是表面上的光吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Light that's only on the surface.
科尔顿·奥格登：光只存在于表面
Kind of, yes.
算是吧 是的
So it's light that will emit from the surface
所以它是从表面发出的光
of a specifically-designated rectangle, effectively, in one direction.
在一个方向上有效地使用特定指定的矩形
So you can define a large area.
所以你可以定义一个很大的区域
For example, maybe you want like a wall strip in your game or something
例如 也许你想在你的游戏中加入一个墙条之类的东西
on the wall to emit light specifically to the left or something like that.
在墙上专门向左或类似的方向发光
That's what an area light is capable of.
这就是区域光的能力所在
Now, area lights are computationally expensive,
现在 区域光在计算上是昂贵的
and so you can only use them when you bake your lighting.
因此 只有在烘焙灯光时才能使用它们
Does anybody remember what baking means when referring to lighting?
有人记得当提到照明时烘焙是什么意思吗？
So baked lighting just means that, instead of real-time lighting,
所以烘焙照明只是意味着 不是实时照明
calculating things dynamically, the light gets calculated one time
动态计算 光只计算一次
and saved, and almost like freezed onto all of the objects in the scene.
并保存 几乎冻结在场景中的所有对象上
And so there are pros and cons to this.
因此 这是有好处也有坏处的
What's a pro to baked lighting, do we think?
我们认为烘焙照明有什么好处呢？
AUDIENCE: It's less computationally intensive.
观众：它的计算量较小
COLTON OGDEN: Less
科尔顿·奥格登：计算量较小
What's a downside to baked lighting?
烘焙照明有什么不利之处？
AUDIENCE: Can't be dynamically affected.
观众：不能受到动态影响
COLTON OGDEN: Can't be dynamically affected.
科尔顿·奥格登：不能受到动态影响
So if you're walking through a baked lighting scene
所以如果你走在一个烘焙的灯光场景中
and you're expecting to cast a shadow on something, or for something
你希望在某件事上投下阴影 或者为某件事
to cast a shadow onto you, it's not going to happen.
给你投下阴影 这是不会发生的
Because the environment's already been--
因为环境已经--
the lighting for that scene has been pre-baked.
该场景的照明已预烘焙
It's almost as if we've just recolored the world in a specific way,
这几乎就像我们刚刚以一种特定的方式重新描绘了世界
but we're not actually doing any lighting calculations.
但我们实际上并没有进行任何照明计算
But this is how lighting worked in, like, the N64 era.
但这就是照明在N64时代的工作方式
And it's how it still works now for certain situations.
这就是它现在在某些情况下仍然起作用的方式
If you know nothing is going to cast a shadow on something,
如果你知道什么都不会给某事蒙上阴影
you can make really nice looking lighting for a scene
您可以为场景制作非常漂亮的灯光
without needing to do it in real time.
而不需要实时进行
You can just bake it, right?
你可以直接烤它 对吗？
So those are the different types of lights.
所以这些是不同类型的灯
So we can see that, in Unity--
所以我们可以看到 在统一组织中--
so if we go here.
所以如果我们走到这里
I'm going to-- so right now we have a directional light.
我要--现在我们有一个平行光
So this directional light is this object here.
所以这个平行光就是这个物体
By default, all-- and you can zoom in as much as you want,
默认情况下 所有--你可以想放大多少就放大多少
but it's sort of like--
但这有点像--
oh, there we go.
哦 又来了
This directional light is only shining in one direction.
这种平行光只朝一个方向照射
So I can move it here.
这样我就可以把它搬到这里来
So currently I'm in--
所以目前我在--
it's a little bit weird to navigate, just
导航有点奇怪 只是
because it's been rotated a little bit.
因为它被稍微旋转了一下
Given that it's a directional light, its rotation--
考虑到它是平行光 它的自转--
So notice how it changes.
所以请注意它是如何变化的
So if I shine it upwards, notice that everything becomes black
所以如果我把它往上照 注意到所有的东西都变黑了
because the lighting is just shining upwards, right?
因为灯光只是向上照射 对吗？
So as if it's coming from below.
所以它就好像是从下面来的
And if I shine it towards there, notice that the lighting
如果我把它照向那里 注意到灯光
on the sphere and the little cube there sort of change a bit, right?
在球体和小立方体上有一些变化 对吗？
Because they're getting affected by the direction of the light a little bit.
因为它们会受到光线方向的影响
But they both get affected the exact same,
但他们都受到了完全相同的影响
because the directional light is omnipresent.
因为平行光无处不在
It's throughout the entire scene.
它贯穿了整个场景
It's a global object.
它是一个全球性的物体
Now if I delete the directional light--
现在如果我删除平行光--
Notice have no light now, so these things just
注意现在没有光 所以这些东西只是
look kind of, like, statically shaded.
看起来就像是静态阴影
You can add a new light through--
你可以添加一个新的光线--
if you right click in your sort of game object view, and then you go over here,
如果你右击你的游戏对象视图 然后你走到这里
you can see we have all the different lights we talked about.
你可以看到我们有我们说过的所有不同的灯
There's also things called reflection probes and light probe groups.
还有一些东西叫做反射探头和光探针组
And those are a little bit more complicated.
而这些都稍微复杂了一点
But those allow you to effectively get pseudo-real-time lighting
但这些可以让你有效地获得伪实时照明
and reflection with baked lighting and reflection.
以及带有烘焙灯光和反射的反射
We won't talk about those in today's lecture.
在今天的课程中 我们不会讨论这些问题
But here's a point light, for example.
但这里有一个点光源 例如
So, let's see, where is it?
那么 让我想想 它在哪里？
It's right over here.
就在这里
So I'm going to move it over here.
所以我要把它移到这里
So you can see it's not global like the directional light was, right?
所以你可以看到它不像平行光那样是全局的 对吗？
It's just affecting this very limited-- and I'm going to zoom in a little bit
它只会影响到这个非常有限的部分--我要把它放大一点
so you can see a little bit better.
这样你就能看得更清楚一点
But it's affecting just sort of these two objects
但它只是影响了这两个物体
relative to where its position is.
相对于它所在的位置
And so this works perfectly for things like lamps in your scene.
因此 这对于场景中的灯之类的东西非常有效
If you want to have a street light, or whether you want to have
如果你想要路灯 或者你想要
maybe like a fire going on in a house.
也许就像房子里着火了一样
Or if you want the power up that we had--
或者 如果你想要我们已经拥有的能量--
or the pickup that we had in the Unity scene, right?
或者是我们在《团结》里的那辆皮卡 对吧？
We have just the--
我们只有--
it's just emitting a purple light that is within a very small radius.
它只是在一个非常小的半径内发出紫色的光
Notice here we can change the color of the light.
请注意 这里我们可以更改灯光的颜色
So if I make it like that--
所以如果我这样做的话--
there we go-- so I'll do that.
这就对了--所以我就这么做
So notice now it's emitting a purple light.
所以请注意 现在它发出了紫色的光
So you can color a light however you want
所以你可以随心所欲地给灯光上色
to produce whatever effects you want.
来产生你想要的任何效果
So fire is not going to emit white light.
所以火不会发出白光
It's probably going to emit like an orange red light.
它很可能会像橙色红光一样发出
Street lights are probably going to emit kind of like a yellow orangey light.
街灯可能会发出一种黄色的橙色光
So depending on what your scene looks like and what you're trying to emulate,
所以取决于你的场景是什么样子以及你想要模仿的是什么
you can accomplish pretty much anything with just these very simple objects.
只需使用这些非常简单的对象 您就可以完成几乎任何事情
So I'm going to get rid of the point light.
所以我要去掉点光源
And then I'm going to create a spotlight.
然后我要创造一个聚光灯
I'm not going to create an area light just because I need to actually bake
我不会仅仅因为需要烘焙而创建区域光
the lighting into the scene.
场景中的灯光
But I will create a spotlight just so we can see what it looks like.
但我将创建一个聚光灯 以便我们可以看到它是什么样子的
Get it in the right position.
把它放在正确的位置
Sometimes it can be a little tough to figure exactly where you are.
有时候 想要弄清楚自己的确切位置可能有点困难
OK, getting close.
好了 快到了
There we go.
我们走吧
Perfect.
完美无缺
So this little spotlight right here is being produced by our object.
所以这里的这个小聚光灯是由我们的物体产生的
So you can see we can move it around.
所以你可以看到我们可以移动它
And then we can apply a cookie to it if we want to, as well.
然后 如果我们想要的话 我们也可以在它上面应用一个cookie
It's right here.
就在这里
So in your-- if you're in a spotlight and you want to apply a texture to it,
所以在你的--如果你在聚光灯下 你想要给它应用一个纹理
just this little cookie--
就这块小饼干--
and it just expects a texture.
它只需要一种质地
So whatever image you want.
所以无论你想要什么形象
And if you're creating a cookie texture, white means full light and black
如果你要创造一种曲奇纹理 白色意味着全光和全黑
means full shadow.
意思是全阴影
And so you can make it a grayscale image.
所以你可以把它变成一个灰度图像
You can make it anywhere in between white and black,
你可以让它在白色和黑色之间的任何地方
which will allow you to produce some interesting effects.
这会让你产生一些有趣的效果
For example, the manual in--
例如 手册中的--
It's not here.
它不在这里
I didn't include the picture here, but the manual
我在这里没有包括图片 但手册
shows there are some kind of like the lights that you put on a stand.
显示有一种类似于你放在展台上的灯
And they have a bunch of LEDs, right?
他们有一堆LED 对吧？
And they're sort of in a grid, and they shoot out a spotlight.
它们就像是在一个网格中 它们发出聚光灯
You can create a cookie that's kind of a grayscale with those gridded lines,
你可以用这些网格线创建一个类似于灰度的曲奇
and it'll shoot light onto the scene as if it's being
它会将光线照射到场景中 就好像它是
broadcast from a sort of grid of LEDs.
从LED的栅格中进行广播
So there's a lot you can do with just some very simple ideas.
因此 只要有一些非常简单的想法 你就可以做很多事情
Those are the kinds of lighting that we can use.
这些都是我们可以使用的照明类型
And in today's lecture, we only really used the point light.
在今天的课程中 我们只使用了点光源
And in the last lecture we used the directional light.
在上一节课中 我们使用了平行光
And spotlights you could, for example, programmatically
和聚光灯 例如 您可以通过编程
change, for example, the rotation of a spotlight,
例如 更改聚光灯的旋转
if you want to have like a swinging spotlight in your scene to illuminate
如果你想在你的场景中有一个摆动的聚光灯来照亮
some wall or some surface.
一些墙壁或表面
There's a lot of cool things you can do with it.
你可以用它做很多很酷的事情
So those are the core types of lights in Unity.
这些是Unity中的核心灯光类型
Does anybody have any questions as to how they're used or how they were.
有没有人对它们的用途有任何疑问
AUDIENCE: For directional light, does it matter
观众：对于定向光
where it's placed or only the direction it's facing?
它的位置还是它面对的方向
COLTON OGDEN: It does not matter-- so for the directional light,
科尔顿·奥格登：这并不重要--所以对于定向光
it does not matter where it's placed.
放在哪里并不重要
You could place it anywhere in your scene--
你可以把它放在场景中的任何地方
00 or some far distance away--
00或更远的地方--
it'll have the exact same effect on the entire scene.
整个场景都会有同样的效果
Any more questions?
还有问题吗
OK.
好的.
Cool, cool.
酷酷
So those are lights.
所以那些是光
Bump mapping, we'll talk about very briefly.
凹凸贴图 我们会简单讨论一下
So bump mapping is--
所以凹凸贴图
we actually do use this in the game.
我们确实在游戏中用到了这个
A bump map effectively is-- so what you see here on the left
凹凸贴图实际上是--所以你在左边看到的
is an actual 3D scene.
是真实的3D场景
These are actual models being shaded in real time.
这些是实时着色的实际模型
Or, not in real time, but they're actually real models being illuminated.
或者 不是实时的 但它们实际上是被照亮的真实模型
In the middle, we can see what's called a bump map, and on the right,
在中间 我们可以看到所谓的凹凸贴图 在右边
we can see a-- that's just a flat--
我们可以看到一个--那只是一个公寓--
like a flat plane.
就像平面一样
With a bump map-- with that same bump map-- applied to it,
用一个凹凸贴图--用同样的凹凸贴图--应用到它
and then illuminated.
然后被照亮
So what a bump map allows us to do is to take a flat wall or flat surface
所以凹凸贴图允许我们做的是取一个平坦的墙或平面
or whatever you want, and then simulate an actual three-dimensional contour,
或者任何你想要的东西 然后模拟一个真实的三维轮廓
three-dimensional bumps, or whatever you want on that surface
三维的凸起 或者任何你想要的东西
without needing to create the actual geometry to make it possible.
而不需要创建实际的几何形状来使其成为可能
And so there are different tools that will allow
所以有不同的工具可以让
you to create bump mapping objects--
创建凹凸贴图对象--
or bump mapping textures.
或凹凸贴图纹理
Often 3D packages will have these, so you can create them.
通常3D包会有这些 所以你可以创建它们
Or other software.
或其他软件
But they are effectively just the encoding
但它们实际上只是
of what are called surface normals.
曲面法线的一部分
So just a vector going from outside of the polygon at that given point.
一个向量从多边形的外部 到给定的点
And they tell the lighting system in Unity,
他们告诉联合照明系统
pretend as if there's actually geometry pointed in that direction
假装好像真的有几何体指向那个方向
when you calculate it.
当你计算它的时候
And so, even though it doesn't distort the geometry in a way that's--
因此 即使它不会扭曲几何图形
like, this is still completely flat.
就像 这仍然是完全平坦的
The lighting thinks that the geometry is kind of, you know, contoured.
灯光让人觉得几何体是一种 你知道的 轮廓
And so it allows us to create--
因此 它允许我们创造--
this is kind of a toy example, but it's actually
这是一个玩具的例子 但它实际上
relevant in the case of walls that have--
与此相关的墙有--
and we covered this last week, just not in as much detail.
我们上周对此进行了报道 只是没有那么详细
But walls that you want to be flat and you
但是你想要变平的墙和你
don't want to have a lot of polygons for, you can create a bump
不想有太多的多边形 你可以创建一个凹凸
map for and apply that bump map.
为凹凸贴图贴图并应用该凹凸贴图
And then when you're rendering it, when you walk past a wall,
然后当你渲染它的时候 当你走过一堵墙时
it's going to look as if the wall actually has cracks and bumps in it,
它看起来就像墙实际上有裂缝和凹凸不平的地方
for a realistic effect.
以获得逼真的效果
And this is used in the game to a slight degree.
而这在游戏中也有轻微的使用
And you can crank it up if you want to.
如果你想的话 你可以把它调高
I didn't on my computer because my specs aren't sufficient.
我没有在我的电脑上 因为我的规格不够
But every texture in today's example has a bump map associated with it.
但今天示例中的每个纹理都有一个与之关联的凹凸贴图
So you can actually see the effect of bump mapping at various degrees of use.
因此 您可以实际看到凹凸贴图在不同使用程度下的效果
The materials here-- I'm going to go--
这里的材料--我要去--
I'm going to load up the scene that has the actual stuff.
我要加载包含实际素材的场景
I'm going to-- actually, I don't need to load up the scene.
我要--事实上 我不需要加载场景
All I need to do is go to the materials.
我所要做的就是去找材料
And the floor, for example.
比如地板
Where is the floor?
楼层在哪里？
Right here.
就在这里
So notice that before, we talked about albedo,
请注意 在前面 我们讨论了反照率
and then I also mentioned normal map.
然后我还提到了法线贴图
So right here, all you really need to do in order
所以就在这里 你真正需要做的就是
to get Unity to detect normal maps-- and this is just
为了让Unity检测法线贴图--这只是
part of the standard shader.
标准着色器的一部分
Normal maps and bump maps, by the way, are effectively synonymous.
顺便说一句 法线贴图和凹凸贴图实际上是同义词
You can just drag your normal map texture
只需拖动法线贴图纹理即可
into this field here, this little square,
进入这片田野 这个小广场
and then give it a degree at which to apply that normal map.
然后给它一个应用法线贴图的度数
And so if you look at this here, you might be able to see--
所以如果你看这里 你可能会看到--
I don't recall.
我不记得了
Yeah, we can sort of see how it changes the texture, right?
是的 我们可以看到它是如何改变质地的 对吗？
So at zero, there's no normal mapping taking place at all.
因此 在零值时 根本不会发生法线贴图
That texture is just completely flat, as if we
这种质地是完全平坦的 就好像我们
had done just the regular apply texture to a sphere.
仅执行了常规的将纹理应用于球体
But the degree at which we apply normal mapping-- so notice that at degree one,
但是我们应用法线映射的程度--所以请注意 在第一次
it kind of looks pretty realistic, as if we've got kind of a stony texture.
它看起来很逼真 就像我们得到了一种石质纹理
And the more we go, the more exaggerated it starts to look, right?
我们走得越多 它看起来就越夸张 对吗？
And you can just keep doing that, and it'll eventually just
你可以继续这样做 最终它会
look really distorted.
看起来真的很扭曲
But that allows you--
但这让你--
and depending on how strong your computer is,
这取决于你的电脑有多强大
you can go higher or lower--
你可以更高或更低--
to affect just how bumpy--
影响到多大的颠簸--
just how strong the bump map, the normal map, affects the lighting rendering.
凹凸贴图、法线贴图对照明渲染的影响程度
So it's that easy to get just a fairly, sort of,
所以很容易就能得到一个相当 有点
extra sense of realism in your scene.
在你的场景中有额外的现实感
So you'll notice, if you're walking through the scene,
所以你会注意到 如果你走在现场
if you turn off lighting it's even easier to see
如果你关掉灯光 就更容易看到
all of the surfaces, the floors, the ceilings, and the walls
所有的表面、地板、天花板和墙壁
have a bump map as well as a texture map.
拥有凹凸贴图和纹理贴图
So that's-- in case you're wondering what these weird colored textures are,
这是--如果你想知道这些奇怪的颜色纹理是什么
RGB or XYZ for the surface normals and their permutations thereof.
曲面法线及其排列的RGB或XYZ
And that's how it gets encoded into this.
这就是它是如何被编码成这个的
And so often you can see--
你经常可以看到--
if you're looking at a bump map and a texture map--
如果你看到的是凹凸贴图和纹理贴图--
you can kind of see together, like, oh, OK this makes sense.
你们可以一起看 就像 哦 好的 这是有意义的
The parts that I would expect to be bumpier or do
我预计会更颠簸或会做的部分
have a correlation to how they look on the actual bump map texture.
与它们在实际凹凸贴图纹理上的外观相关
You can see it here.
你可以在这里看到它
Everything that is bumpy or contoured is very visible in the bump map.
凹凸贴图中所有凹凸不平或有轮廓的东西都非常明显
And that's just by nature of the way the data is encoded.
这只是数据编码方式的本质
So any questions as to how bump maps work or what they are
所以任何关于凹凸贴图如何工作或它们是什么的问题
or how to use them in Unity?
或者如何在Unity中使用它们？
All right.
好的
Cool.
凉爽的
So now we're going to start getting a little bit more
所以现在我们要开始得到一点
into how this all comes together in our maze on our game,
这一切是如何在我们的游戏迷宫中结合在一起的
and we'll talk about maze generation.
我们会讨论迷宫的生成
So I'm going to just start up the scene here.
我就从这里开始
So I'm in the actual play scene.
所以我在真实的游戏场景中
So in scenes, I loaded up play as before.
所以在场景中 我像以前一样加载播放
I'm going to hit Play.
我要按播放键了
I'm going to turn off my sound, just because the creepy sound
我要关掉我的声音 因为那令人毛骨悚然的声音
is a little disorienting after a while.
过一段时间会有点迷失方向
And then I'm going to--
然后我要...
actually, I'm going to go to a 2 by 3 view.
实际上 我打算去一个2乘3的视图
And then hit Play.
然后点击播放
So we have the regular game view down here below.
所以我们在下面有一个常规的游戏视图
And then also, if I zoom out, you can see that our scene was empty before,
然后 如果我缩小 你可以看到我们的场景之前是空的
but now we've got a maze.
但现在我们有个迷宫
And currently it's not very visible at all because one,
目前它还不是很明显
we're applying fog, right?
我们要用雾对吧
And recall fog allows us to effectively add color
而回忆雾让我们能够有效地为
to objects that are farther away from us.
到离我们更远的物体
And two, there's a ceiling on top of our--
第二我们的屋顶上有天花板
a roof on top of our maze.
在我们的迷宫上盖个屋顶
So it's actually blocking out what the maze looks like.
所以它实际上挡住了迷宫的样子
So we can fairly easily make a couple of changes
所以我们可以很容易地做一些改变
here in order to see our maze a little bit better.
为了更好地观察我们的迷宫
So I'm going to go to Window, I'm going to go to Lighting, Settings.
所以我要去窗口 我要去灯光 设置
And so if you go to Window, Lighting, Settings,
所以如果你去窗口 灯光 设置
those are your sort of global Unity lighting settings.
这些是全局Unity照明设置
You can set your skybox, you can set environment lighting,
你可以设置你的天空盒 你可以设置环境照明
you can set things like fog, you can choose how things are baked.
你可以设置像雾这样的东西 你可以选择如何烘烤东西
There's a lot of things here.
这里有很多东西
We won't cover nearly all of them.
我们不会涵盖几乎所有的
We will cover a few of them.
我们将涵盖其中的一些
Environment lighting is a big one.
环境照明是一个大问题
That's actually how we're lighting the scene in this game.
这就是我们在这个游戏中如何照亮场景
So all of the lighting that's not--
所以所有的灯光
well, all of the lighting is environment lighting.
那么所有的照明都是环境照明
That's how we're doing it.
我们就是这么做的
We're doing it with color.
我们要用颜色来做
So notice that you can choose Skybox, Gradient, and Color.
因此 请注意 您可以选择天空框 渐变和颜色
So if you choose skybox Environment. lighting, it's going to have sort of--
所以如果你选择天空盒环境 灯光 它会有一种--
it's going to look kind of like this skybox that we have here.
它看起来会有点像我们这里的这个天空盒子
This sort of in the far distance, looks blue.
这个在很远的地方 看起来是蓝色的
Kind of a little bit more natural.
更自然一点
But I didn't-- but when it's applied to our scene,
但我没有--但当它应用到我们的场景时
it doesn't look quite the way we want it to look.
它看起来和我们想要的不太一样
So what we went with instead was just color.
所以我们选择的只是颜色
And I chose this sort of murky greenish brownish color.
我选择了这种墨绿色的棕色调
And that gave the result that I was looking for.
这就给了我想要的结果
But you can make this any color you want to.
但是你可以把它做成任何你想要的颜色
We can make this some sort of bright yellow color.
我们可以把这个做成某种鲜艳的黄色
I have no idea what this is going to look like.
我不知道这会是什么样子
This is probably going to look horrible, but--
这可能会看起来很可怕 但是--
Yep.
是啊
I mean, actually, this--
我是说 实际上 这...
is in a weird way this kind of looks interesting.
以一种奇怪的方式这种看起来很有趣
It actually looks closer to the original Dreadhalls game than what I did.
事实上 它看起来比我所做的更接近最初的恐怖大厅游戏
But it's not very scary.
但这并不是很可怕
Kind of looks like we're in a pyramid.
看起来我们就像在金字塔里
That is-- am I able to go back?
那就是--我能回去吗？
No.
不是的
OK.
好的
Well, I screwed up the color.
好吧 我把颜色搞砸了
Now I'm trying to find kind of what color I had before.
现在我想知道我以前是什么颜色的
It's kind of like a nasty green.
它就像一种难看的绿色
Kind of like that.
就像这样
That's probably good enough.
这可能已经足够好了
OK.
好的
Something like that.
差不多是这样
And so we play it again, we can see we're back to the nasty dark color.
所以我们再玩一次 我们可以看到我们又回到了令人讨厌的深色
But that's environment lighting.
但那是环境照明
So it applies a lighting, uniform, just ambience.
因此 它应用了一种照明 统一 只是氛围
Kind of like a directional light, but it doesn't have a direction.
有点像平行光 但它没有方向
It just applies to everything in your scene at a given intensity.
它只适用于场景中给定强度的所有内容
And that is how we are lighting our scene.
这就是我们如何照亮我们的场景
It's that easy.
就这么简单
Just environment lighting in our scene and our lighting scene window.
只有场景中的环境照明和我们的照明场景窗口
Now, the other important thing here is the fog.
现在 这里另一件重要的事情是雾
So fog is as easy--
所以雾是很容易的--
almost as easy as just clicking this button here that says fog,
几乎和点击这里的这个按钮一样简单 上面写着雾
and then choosing a color for it, probably.
然后可能会为它选择一种颜色
You can choose the density, so obviously if it's a higher density fog
您可以选择密度 因此很明显 如果是密度较高的雾
it's going to look as if you're in a foggier place.
它会让你看起来像是在一个雾气更大的地方
It's going to sum the color to things that are closer to you
它会把颜色加到离你更近的东西上
faster than it would if you had a lower density fog.
比具有较低密度雾时的速度更快
And there are some other features here, some of which
这里还有其他一些功能 其中一些
I'm not terribly familiar with.
我不是很熟悉
But for the sake of today's example, just the click--
但就今天的例子而言 只是点击一下--
make sure fog is selected.
确保选择了雾
And then click, make sure you have the right color for your fog.
然后单击 确保您的雾具有正确的颜色
So if you have like a ridiculous red color for your fog,
所以如果你的雾是可笑的红色
it's probably going to look weird.
它可能会看起来很奇怪
Yep.
是啊
But you can see how you can do all kinds of weird effects
但你可以看到你可以做各种奇怪的效果
just by adding these things together.
只要把这些东西加在一起
Like, if you want to have the effect of being in some sort of, like--
就像 如果你想要有某种效果 就像--
I don't know, noxious foreign world, maybe you want like a purple fog
我不知道 有毒的异国他乡 也许你想要一片紫雾
instead of like a dark green fog or whatever.
而不是像深绿色的雾之类的
That's super easy.
这太简单了
You produce a lot of very basic but effective effects that way.
通过这种方式 你会产生很多非常基本但有效的效果
Let me find-- I think it was just that kind of the same nasty green color.
让我找找--我想它就是那种令人讨厌的绿色
AUDIENCE: How you bring this screen up again?
观众：你是怎么让这个屏幕再次出现的？
The one that says lighting?
上面写着闪电的那个？
COLTON OGDEN: So to bring up this lighting screen, all you need to do
科尔顿·奥格登：要调出这个照明屏 你需要做的就是
is, if you're on a Mac--
就是 如果你用的是Mac--
I think in Windows it's the same thing-- there's
我认为在Windows中也是一样的--有
a Window option in the top menu.
顶部菜单中的窗口选项
Window, and then Lighting here, and then Settings.
窗口 然后是照明 然后是设置
And so this will bring you to all of the settings that are pertinent to at least
因此 这将带您了解至少与以下内容相关的所有设置
today's example.
今天的例子
And so we're not using any lights in our scene
所以我们在场景中没有使用任何灯光
that we talked about before, at least for the lighting of the scene itself.
我们之前谈到的 至少对于场景本身的照明来说
Now, there are point lights being used for the pickups,
现在 有点光源被用于皮卡
and I'll show you that in a second.
我马上就给你们展示一下
But what I wanted to illustrate was how we can look at our maze
但我想要说明的是我们如何看待我们的迷宫
after it's been generated.
在它被生成之后
And so what we need to do first--
所以我们首先要做的是--
notice that before we couldn't really see our maze at a distance
请注意 在此之前 我们在远处看不到迷宫
because it was just purely dark green because of the fog.
因为因为有雾 它是纯深绿色的
It was adding green to that geometry because it was so far away.
它给那个几何图形增加了绿色 因为它离我们太远了
So I'm going to disable fog for now.
所以我现在要禁用雾
It'll actually remember your settings, which is kind of nice.
它实际上会记住你的设置 这是一种不错的选择
So just going to disable fog.
所以只需禁用雾即可
And I'm going to actually add a directional light to the scene.
我要在场景中添加一个平行光
So I'm going to go here, add a directional light.
所以我要在这里加一个平行光
And then I'm going to hit Play again.
然后我要再按一次播放
So now, our scene is lit.
现在 我们的场景被点亮了
And, you know, it looks a lot different, a lot less scary.
而且 你知道 它看起来很不同 不那么可怕
And we can see our maze lot better.
我们可以更清楚地看到我们的迷宫
We can actually see that it is a collection of blocks.
我们实际上可以看到它是块的集合
It's tiled blocks.
它是瓷砖砌成的
Now, we can't see into the maze because the maze has a roof.
现在 我们看不到迷宫 因为迷宫有屋顶
So what I did was I just made a generated roof,
所以我所做的就是做了一个生成的屋顶
an option in the script, and so if you unselect that and then we try again,
脚本中的一个选项 因此如果您取消选择该选项 然后我们重试
now we can see our maze.
现在我们可以看到我们的迷宫了
So this is what our mazes look like.
这就是我们的迷宫的样子
And so the cool thing about Unity, which I really love,
所以关于团结的酷的事情 我真的很喜欢
is just this ability to look through your scene independent
仅仅是这种通过场景观看的能力是独立的
of the actual game, just to help debug.
的实际游戏 只是为了帮助调试
It's hard to know if you're generating your maze correctly
很难知道您是否正确地生成了迷宫
when you're creating it in 3D.
当你在3D中创建它的时候
You know, in 2D you can easily just look at it.
你知道 在2D中 你可以很容易地看到它
But in 3D, especially in a first-person game, you can't really see it.
但在3D游戏中 尤其是在第一人称游戏中 你看不到它
So being able to split your view like this-- the scene and the game--
所以能够像这样分割你的视野--场景和游戏--
and actually see, oh, my algorithm's working, or it's not working.
实际上看到 哦 我的算法在起作用 或者它不起作用
Super helpful.
超级有帮助
So we can see that it is carving a maze for us.
所以我们可以看到它正在为我们雕刻一个迷宫
It looks a little bit weird.
它看起来有点奇怪
It's not a traditional maze in the sense that it has the classic maze
这不是一个传统的迷宫 因为它有经典的迷宫
shape to it.
对它进行整形
But it effectively functions as a maze, and it works very well
但它实际上起到了迷宫的作用 而且工作得很好
for its intended purpose.
为了它的预期目的
And the algorithm is incredibly simple, and we'll talk about that.
算法非常简单 我们将会讨论这一点
So that's our maze.
这就是我们的迷宫
I'm going to go ahead and revert all of the--
我将继续并还原所有--
I think if I just reload the scene it should just revert it.
我想如果我重新加载场景 它应该会恢复原状
Don't save.
不要存钱
Yep.
是啊
OK, so everything's been reverted, all the lighting and everything.
好的 一切都恢复了 所有的灯光和一切都恢复了
Just going to do a sanity check and make sure.
我去做个心理检查 确保
Yep.
是啊
Everything works perfectly well.
一切都运转得很好
So anybody have any ideas as to where to get
所以有没有人知道到哪里去
started if we were to implement a 3D maze?
如果我们要实施3D迷宫就开始了？
AUDIENCE: The way I did it once before is
观众：我以前做过一次是
you put a bunch of x's where you want something to be drawn in an array.
你把一堆x放在你想要在数组中画东西的地方
And then you loop through the array and draw, instantiate the walls.
然后循环遍历数组并绘制、实例化墙壁
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
So create an array.
因此 创建一个数组
Populate it with x's where you want--
在你想要的地方填上x--
data wherever you want something to be instantiated,
无论您想要实例化什么数据
then loop over and instantiate everything.
然后循环并实例化所有内容
That's exactly how it works.
这就是它的工作原理
Now, in terms of actually creating the maze,
现在 从创造迷宫的角度来看
do you have any ideas as to what--
你有没有什么想法--
how would you go about implementing a simple maze generator?
您将如何着手实现一个简单的迷宫生成器？
And there are, obviously, very complicated maze generation algorithms,
显然 有非常复杂的迷宫生成算法
so nothing terribly fancy, but just a simple--
所以没什么特别花哨的 只是一个简单的--
how would you make a maze?
你会怎么做一个迷宫？
AUDIENCE: So it's random?
观众：所以这是随机的？
Or--
或者--
COLTON OGDEN: It's random.
科尔顿·奥格登：这是随机的
So starting with the idea that we have an array, right?
所以从我们有一个数组的想法开始 对吗？
It's got to be a 2D array because we have two axes upon which
它必须是一个2D阵列 因为我们有两个轴
we're generating things here.
我们在这里创造了一些东西
Even though we're in a 3D environment, we don't need a 3D array.
即使我们在3D环境中 我们也不需要3D阵列
We just need a 2D array.
我们只需要一个二维数组
Because if there is a positive value for wherever
因为如果在任何地方都有一个正值
we want to generate a block in our 3D maze,
我们想要在3D迷宫中生成一个积木
we just generate a column of blocks.
我们只生成一列块
We don't need to worry about a third dimension, right?
我们不需要担心第三维空间 对吗？
Our maze isn't taking into consideration multiple levels, at which point
我们的迷宫没有考虑多个层次 在这一点上
we would need to maybe consider three dimensions.
我们可能需要考虑三个维度
And even still, you can still divide those into separate 2D arrays of mazes.
即使这样 你仍然可以把它们分成不同的二维迷宫阵列
We just have an x and a y.
我们只有一个x和一个y
So how would we get started--
那么我们该如何开始呢--
what would we start populating the arra-- let's say we have an array,
我们将从什么开始填充ARRA--假设我们有一个数组
it's just a bunch of zeros, right?
这只是一堆零 对吧？
What are we populating with the array after we have initialized it?
在初始化数组之后 我们要用它填充什么？
AUDIENCE: So I'm thinking maybe you would kind of start
观众：所以我在想 也许你可以从
off with just four walls add corridors, maybe?
如果只有四面墙 也许会增加走廊？
COLTON OGDEN: So start with a bunch of walls and then add corridors.
科尔顿·奥格登：所以从一堆墙开始 然后增加走廊
That's exactly what we do.
这正是我们要做的
The algorithm is actually pretty simple.
这个算法实际上非常简单
So I'll try and maybe draw a little bit, just to see
所以我会试着画一点 只是为了看看
if I can illustrate how this works.
如果我能说明这是如何运作的
AUDIENCE: How do you make sure that you can get from one side to the other
观众：你如何确保你能从一边到另一边
and there's no wall in between?
中间没有墙吗？
COLTON OGDEN: By making sure that every thing that you change is orthogonal.
科尔顿·奥格登：通过确保你改变的每一件事都是正交的
Every block-- every step that you move is orthogonal.
每一块--你移动的每一步都是垂直的
That will ensure that you start at one point, end at another point,
这将确保你在一个点开始 在另一个点结束
and those points will always be accessible to one another,
而这些点将始终可以相互访问
just by virtue of how simple the algorithm is
仅仅是因为算法是多么的简单
and the orthogonality of it.
以及它的正交性
So if we start with walls--
所以如果我们从墙开始--
so 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1.
所以1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1
These are all-- in the distro, these are all Booleans
这些都是--在发行版中 这些都是布尔值
because we don't need-- we only need zeros and ones so we're just
因为我们不需要--我们只需要0和1 所以我们
going to use true and false.
将使用True和False
We don't need to use integers for that.
为此 我们不需要使用整数
So this is our starting maze here.
这就是我们从这里开始的迷宫
And actually I'm going to add another dimension because--
实际上 我要增加另一个维度 因为--
or not another dimension, but another size,
或者不是另一个维度 而是另一个大小
just because the walls always need to stay-- to be there.
只是因为墙总是需要留在那里--才能在那里
These are basically untouchable.
这些基本上是碰不到的
I'm going to try and draw that as best I can.
我会尽我所能画出来的
Right.
正确的
So we effectively have this as our working area for creating a maze.
因此 我们有效地将这里作为创建迷宫的工作区
Because we want this to be--
因为我们希望这是--
we want walls no matter what because we don't
我们无论如何都想要墙 因为我们不想
want our person to be able to walk outside the maze
希望我们的人能够走出迷宫
or see the outside world, ever.
或者看到外面的世界 永远不会
We want them to be locked in.
我们希望他们被锁在里面
So we have all of these ones here, these trues, effectively.
所以我们这里有所有的这些 这些真实的 有效的
And so all we need to do is start at some random position,
所以我们所需要做的就是从某个随机的位置开始
let's say this value.
让我们假设这个值
At 3, 2-- or, well, it's actually, technically
在3 2--或者 嗯 实际上 从技术上讲
it's 2, 3 because we index at y and then x in a 2D array.
它是2 3 因为我们在一个二维数组中索引y 然后是x
So we go 2, 3.
所以我们开始2 3
We go here.
我们从这里开始
And then we basically can move either left--
然后我们基本上可以向左移动--
or we can move either left or right or up or down.
或者我们可以向左或向右或向上或向下移动
But we can't move both at the same time.
但我们不能同时搬家
And why can't we move both at the same time?
为什么我们不能同时搬家呢？
Let's say that we're-- let's say, first of all, let me say that we're--
比方说我们--比方说 首先 让我说 我们是--
let's say we're going to carve our way through the maze.
假设我们要在迷宫中凿出一条路
So we're going to turn these ones into zeros, but we can only move either--
所以我们要把这些1变成0 但我们只能移动--
we can only move orthogonally, meaning left or right up or down.
我们只能垂直移动 意思是向左或向右 向上或向下
We can't move diagonally.
我们不能沿对角线移动
So we can only--
所以我们只能...
let's say we have an x move, right?
假设我们有一个x移动 对吗？
And a y move.
一步一步走
And those can be set to--
而这些可以设置为--
by default they're 0, so we're basically saying,
默认情况下 它们是0 所以我们基本上是说
where on this step of the generation are we going to move?
在这一代人的这一步上 我们将走向何方？
And actually, technically, it's direction because we're-- the way that
实际上 从技术上讲 这是方向 因为我们--这种方式
we do it is via directions.
我们是通过指示来做的
AUDIENCE: So if you're moving down, then what's in front of you
观众：如果你在往下走 那么你面前的是什么
will have no wall.
将不会有围墙
And there'll be walls on either side of you except for where you came from.
除了你来自的地方 你的两边都会有墙
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
So if you're here and they move down, this is going to be 0,
所以如果你在这里 他们向下移动 这将是0
this is going to be 0, and so those points are linked.
这将是0 所以这些点是相连的
And then from there we're going to move in a given direction.
然后我们将从那里朝一个给定的方向移动
And so all of tho-- let's say they move here.
所以所有这些--比方说他们搬到了这里
All of those are going to be linked.
所有这些都将被联系在一起
And so if we move here, all of those are going to be linked.
因此 如果我们搬到这里 所有这些都将联系在一起
Just by virtue of the fact that we're moving orthogonally,
仅仅是因为我们是垂直移动的
we can't create a maze that's unreachable.
我们不能创造一个遥不可及的迷宫
Because the way that--
因为这种方式--
just by virtue of the fact they're moving orthogonally.
仅仅是因为它们是垂直运动的
Now if we move diagonally, if I were to move here, right?
如果我们沿对角线移动 如果我移动到这里 对吗？
There's walls right here and then two spaces there.
这里有墙 那里有两个空间
That's not going to work because we can't access that.
这是行不通的 因为我们无法访问它
We see a-- we're going to see a cube here and a cube here.
我们看到一个--我们会在这里看到一个立方体 在这里看到一个立方体
And we're going to see-- we won't be able to move diagonally through walls.
我们将会看到--我们将不能沿对角线穿过墙壁
So that's why we need to ensure that we only
这就是为什么我们需要确保我们只有
move either in the x or y direction, not both at once.
在x或y方向上移动 而不是同时朝两个方向移动
And so what the algorithm does is it randomly chooses should I move x
所以算法所做的就是随机选择我是否应该移动x
or should I move y.
或者我应该换个位置
And should I move positive or negative.
我应该采取积极的还是消极的态度
So it'll do-- math dot random, equal--
所以它会做的--数学上的点随机 相等--
you know, two equals 1.
你知道 二等于一
Effectively in the code it's random dot value, less than 0.5,
有效地在代码中它是随机的点值 小于0.5
because random dot value in Unity gives you 0 to 1 as a float.
因为Unity中的随机点值会将0到1表示为浮点数
So you say if random dot value less than 0.5,
所以你说如果随机点值小于0.5
which is a random chance between true and false, effectively 50%--
这是真与假之间的随机机会 有效率为50%--
move in x or move in y.
移入x或移入y
And then same thing, but should I move in the negative or positive direction?
然后是同样的事情 但我应该朝着积极还是消极的方向前进呢？
So if I'm here, I'm thinking, OK, let's see.
所以如果我在这里 我在想 好的 让我们看看
X move or y move?
X移动还是y移动？
Again it's going to be an x move, so I'm going to move either left or right.
再一次 这将是一个x移动 所以我将向左或向右移动
OK, so am I going to move either negative one or one
好的 我要把负数移到1还是1
step, one to the right or to the left?
一步 向右走还是向左走？
So if it's negative 1 and that is going to move to the left, right?
所以如果它是负1 它会向左移动 对吗？
And if it's positive 1 it's going to move to the right.
如果它是正1 它就会向右移动
So that's the essence of the algorithm, just looped over a bunch of times.
所以这就是算法的本质 只是循环了一堆次
Whenever I move to another tile, turn that into a zero.
每当我移动到另一块瓷砖时 就把它变成零
So actually, this becomes a zero.
所以实际上 这变成了零
Change the color.
更改颜色
So this will become a zero.
所以这会变成零
So that's now an empty space.
所以现在那是一片空地
And in the code, that instantly teleports the character to that space,
在代码中 它会立即将角色传送到那个空间
too.
也是
So we know that our character is always going to be in an empty space,
所以我们知道我们的角色总是在一个空白的空间里
because he gets placed in the first open space that gets generated in the maze.
因为他被安置在迷宫中产生的第一个开放空间
And so let's say x move is equal to negative 1 on this iteration.
在这个迭代中 假设x移动等于负1
So let's say we're looping until we've cleared x blocks.
假设我们一直在循环 直到我们清除了x个块
So I want to clear-- let's say I want to clear five blocks.
所以我想清理--比方说我想清理五个街区
So to clear equals 5.
所以清除等于5
That's how many blocks--
这就是街区的数量--
when we've cleared that many blocks, we're done with the maze generator.
当我们清除了那么多街区 我们就完成了迷宫生成器
So cleared one, so our current counter is one.
所以清除了一个 所以我们目前的计数器是一个
So x, we get-- flip a coin.
所以x 我们得到--抛硬币
We're moving to the x direction by negative 1.
我们以负1的速度向x方向移动
So we move to here, and then we turn this into a zero.
所以我们移到这里 然后我们把这个变成零
Now, this implementation of the algorithm moves one step at a time.
现在 算法的这种实现一次前进一步
And so because of its randomness, what this ends up doing is
因此 由于它的随机性 它最终所做的是
it produces very large chunks of deformed space,
它会产生很大的变形空间
just because the crawler is just constantly moving around,
仅仅因为爬行器在不停地移动
kind of, like, haphazardly.
有点 就像 很随意
So what's a refinement that we can make to this algorithm
那么 我们可以对该算法进行哪些改进呢
to make it look a little bit more like corridors or like hallways?
让它看起来更像走廊或走廊？
AUDIENCE: Just keep going until you hit the other wall?
观众：一直走到你撞到另一面墙？
In the same direction?
是同一个方向吗？
COLTON OGDEN: You could do that, yeah, keep
科尔顿·奥格登：你可以这样做 是的 留着
going until you hit the other wall.
一直走到你撞到另一面墙
The result of that--
其结果是--
you mean to hit the side of the maze?
你的意思是撞到迷宫的一边？
Yeah, because it-- well, if you did that,
是的 因为它--好吧 如果你这么做了
it would effectively just be like--
它实际上就像是--
it would kind of be--
这会有点--
it might work in some cases, but it will be very long hallways
在某些情况下可能行得通 但走廊会很长
and not a lot of turns or anything like that.
而且没有太多的转弯或类似的事情
So the result, what we actually want to do, is when we flip a coin
所以结果 我们真正想要做的是 当我们抛硬币时
and we say x move or y move, we want to also say times to move.
我们说x移动或y移动 我们也想说移动的次数
We want to create a new variable called number of times to move, effectively.
我们希望有效地创建一个名为Numbers to Move的新变量
To move, and then we just set that to a random number between 1,
移动 然后我们将其设置为1之间的随机数
so we're going to move 1 tile, or the size of the maze minus 2.
我们要移动1块瓷砖 或者说迷宫的大小减去2
Taking in consideration both walls, right?
把两面墙都考虑进去 对吧？
So let's say we get the--
所以我们假设我们得到了--
let's say we-- let's say we did x move minus 1,
假设我们--假设我们做了x移动减去1
and we only got to move equal to 1, right?
我们只需要移动等于1 对吗？
So we only move here.
所以我们只搬到这里
We move once in this direction, so we've got two spaces.
我们朝这个方向移动一次 所以我们有两个空间
And then let's say we flip a coin again and then we got y move--
然后让我们再次抛硬币 然后我们开始行动--
positive 1.
正1
And then two move, we got two.
再走两步 我们就有两个了
So we're going to move two directions in the y-axis by one.
所以我们要在y轴上移动两个方向 一个方向
So this is a result of us going down here, so we go 0 and then 0.
这是我们往下走的结果 所以我们先是0 然后是0
And so the effect of this is that we move--
因此 这样做的效果是我们移动--
we can move in more than just one block at a time
我们一次可以搬进不止一个街区
and avoid the sort of random, like, haphazard, weird, organic, large room
避免那种随机的、随意的、奇怪的、有机的大房间
aesthetic that we want.
我们想要的美感
If we want like a hallway, grid-like, dungeon looking room generator, right?
如果我们想要一个走廊 网格状 看起来像地牢的房间发电机 对吗？
Now there's a caveat to this, and that is if we start here, for example,
这里有一个警告 那就是如果我们从这里开始 例如
and then we want to--
然后我们想
let's say we flip a coin.
我们来抛硬币决定吧
It's x move, but it's positive four.
是x移动 但它是正4.
We can't obviously move four tiles to the right because one,
我们显然不能把四块瓷砖移到右边
it will go into our walls on the outside, and two,
它会从外面进入我们的墙 第二
it's actually beyond the bounds of our array.
它实际上超出了数组的范围
So we need to clamp that value down.
所以我们需要压制这个价值
When we add 1 to our value, to wherever our x--
当我们给我们的值加1时 无论x--
we have to basically keep pointers.
我们基本上都要保留指针
We keep pointer to whichever tile we're currently at.
我们保持指针指向我们当前所在的瓷砖
We need to keep--
我们得保持...
when we actually go to the next tile in our step,
当我们实际上在我们的步骤中转到下一个瓦片时
we need to clamp that value within the range of our walls.
我们需要把这个值限制在我们的墙的范围内
So we need to clamp between one--
所以我们需要夹在
so because we don't want to be at zero--
因为我们不想为零
we want to clamp it between one and main size minus two, actually.
我们想把它夹在1和主尺寸减2之间
Because we want to make sure that we don't go any farther than this one
因为我们要确保我们不会走得比这更远
here.
这里.
Does that make sense?
这有道理吗？
This is how-- that is effectively how our generator works.
这就是发电机的工作原理
It's a step beyond just the move one block at a time,
这比一次只移动一个街区更进一步
just because the mazes look away too empty and weird.
就因为迷宫看起来太空旷怪异了
With this approach where you're moving in a direction,
通过这种方法 你朝着一个方向前进
and for a random number of tiles as opposed to just one at a time,
并且对于随机数量的瓦片而不是一次仅一个瓦片
you actually get pretty nice looking, simple mazes.
你实际上得到的是一个很漂亮的 简单的迷宫
This isn't how actual maze generation works, for mazes that you would see
这不是真正的迷宫生成的工作原理 对于你会看到的迷宫
and an actual maze that you do in, like, a crossword puzzle book or a maze book
和一个真正的迷宫 就像在一本填字游戏书或迷宫书中一样
or something.
什么的
Those are more complicated.
那些更复杂
But this solution works well.
但这个解决方案效果很好
It's very fast and very cheap, and actually pretty simple to understand.
它非常快 非常便宜 实际上很容易理解
So any questions as to how the maze generator-- the algorithm, at least
有关于迷宫生成器的问题吗至少是算法
as applied to our 2D, array works?
应用到我们的2D阵列中 是否有效？
All right.
好吧
Cool.
酷了
That's the-- that's basically the gist of it.
基本上就是这么回事
So we're going to take a break here for about five minutes, and then as soon
我们先休息五分钟
as we get back we'll dive a little bit more
回来的时候我们会再下潜一点
into sort of how the character controller works, and the pickup,
角色控制器是如何工作的 还有拾取器
and a few other aspects of the game.
以及游戏的其他方面
All right, welcome back to Lecture 9.
好了 欢迎回到第九课
So before the break we were talking about the way
休息之前我们讨论了
that we implemented procedural maze generation.
我们实现了程序化的迷宫生成
So a fairly simple algorithm that creates this sort of hallway
所以一个相当简单的算法
look where we can easily get lost.
看看哪里容易迷路
But they aren't technically mazes in the traditional sense
但它们不是传统意义上的迷宫
like you might have seen growing up in puzzle books and such.
就像你在益智书中看到的那样
Another pitch for Catlike Coding, because his articles are amazing.
另一个推销猫式编码 因为他的文章是惊人的
He has another one on how he did a maze generator.
他还有一个关于他如何做迷宫生成器的
And in this one, beyond just regular blocks--
在这一个 除了普通的街区--
oh, I'm sorry.
哦对不起
I didn't have the slide there on that thing.
我没把幻灯片放在那上面
So this is a screenshot of another article
这是另一篇文章的截图
from Catlike Coding where he talks about how to make his own maze generator.
他在书中谈到了如何制作自己的迷宫生成器
And the cool thing about his is that he has
他最酷的地方在于
a bunch of different geometry involved in the scene.
一堆不同的几何图形
It's not just blocks.
不仅仅是街区
He has doors and windows and other things.
他有门窗和其他东西
And his algorithm is a little bit different than mine
他的算法和我的有点不同
and produces some pretty interesting looking things.
并产生了一些非常有趣的东西
And you can see here, also, it has a view of the scene
你可以看到 它也有一个场景
sort of superimposed on the actual scene, which
叠加在真实的场景上
he does with a trick using two cameras.
他用两个摄像头做了个小把戏
So here's another maze slash dungeon generator article
所以这里的另一个迷宫斜线地牢生成器的文章
that I really like where he creates sort of like Dungeons
我真的很喜欢他创造的地牢
and Dragons-style generators.
和龙式发电机
And this is sort of pertinent to my interests as a developer
这和我作为一个开发者的兴趣有关
because I really love roguelikes and dungeon generators and RPGs,
因为我真的很喜欢Roguelike和地牢生成器和RPG
but he goes into extensive detail on how to make
但他详细介绍了如何
a really nice and efficient 2D maze slash
一个非常漂亮高效的2D迷宫斜线
dungeon generator that produces really nice looking dungeons.
地牢生成器 产生非常好看的地牢
As you can see here, it's got a very variable layout, lots of corridors
如你所见 它的布局非常多变 有很多走廊
and rooms and stuff like that.
房间之类的东西
So implementing some like this in Unity would be really cool,
所以在Unity中实现这样的功能会很酷
and there's a plethora of generators and assets
有太多的发电机和资产
like this that will do the same kind of thing in Unity
在Unity中做同样的事情
available in the asset store.
可在资产商店中使用
So you don't have to make this yourself most of the time.
所以大部分时间你不必自己做这个
You can create-- you can just go find either free or paid assets that
你可以创建--你可以去找免费或付费的资产
will do all this for you and save you a tremendous amount of time.
它会为你做所有这些 并为你节省大量的时间
And how much of them are also very customizable, too,
其中有多少是可以定制的
so that you can tailor the generator to fit the demand of your game.
这样你就可以定制发电机 以满足你的游戏的需求
So we saw how the lighting works in our game.
我们看到了游戏中的灯光是如何工作的
We've seen the maze, sort of how, it's generated, what it looks like.
我们已经看到了迷宫 它是如何产生的 它是什么样子的
We have not taken a look yet at the character controller.
我们还没有看过角色控制器
So we'll briefly just take a look at that.
所以我们会简单地看一下
It's actually incredibly easy to do in Unity, at least
至少在Unity中
to get something fairly basic up and running.
让一些基本的东西开始运行
The way that we get a FPS controller in the case of our game is Unity has,
在我们的游戏中 我们获得FPS控制器的方式是Unity
which I alluded to before, a set of built-in standard asset
我之前提到过 一套内置的标准资产
packs that allow people getting used to the game engine,
让人们习惯游戏引擎的包
or just trying to bootstrap their game, up
或者只是想引导他们的游戏
and running with some very basic components.
和运行一些非常基本的组件
Very basic things that are super helpful for getting your game running.
非常基本的东西 对让你的游戏运行非常有帮助
So actually we used the prototyping standard assets pack for our pickup.
所以实际上我们使用了原型标准资产包作为我们的皮卡
We use the characters one for the character controller, the FPS
我们使用字符一为字符控制器 FPS
controller.
controller.
So if you're in a fresh project and you just go to Import Package
所以如果你在一个新的项目中
and you import this character thing here, it'll import into your game.
你把这个角色导入到游戏里
So that you can immediately use the prefabs that it gives you to create
这样你就可以立即使用它给你的预制件来创建
a character object.
字符对象
So it will, by default, just put it in your assets folder.
所以默认情况下 它会把它放在你的资产文件夹里
Underneath Standard Assets, and then Characters,
下面是标准资产 然后是角色
and then there's a first-person folder.
还有一个第一人称文件夹
And within the first-person folder there's
在第一人称的文件夹里
a prefabs folder which has the FPS controller game object.
预置文件夹 其具有FPS控制器游戏对象
And so all you need to do is just drag it into the scene,
所以你所需要做的就是把它拖到场景中
and then that becomes your default camera.
然后这就成了你的默认摄像头
AUDIENCE: That comes with Unity?
观众：这是Unity自带的吗？
COLTON OGDEN: It comes with Unity, correct.
科尔顿·奥格登：它是统一的 对吧
That's just a standard asset.
这只是一项标准资产
AUDIENCE: And it's always in the prefabs folder?
观众：它总是在预制的文件夹里吗？
COLTON OGDEN: It's always in the-- the FPS controller will always be in the--
科尔顿·奥格登：它总是在--FPS控制器总是在--
so you have to import it first.
所以你必须先把它导入
You have to import the asset package.
您必须导入资产包
The characters package.
角色包
Once you've imported the characters package,
一旦导入了Characters包
you'll go into Standard Assets in your assets folder.
您将进入Assets文件夹中的Standard Assets
There'll be a new folder called Standard Assets.
将会有一个名为Standard Assets的新文件夹
Within Standard Assets you'll go to Characters, then First Person, and then
在Standard Assets中 您将转到Characters 然后是第一人称 然后是
Prefabs, and then that's where you'll find the FPS controller.
预制板 然后你就会在那里找到FPS控制器
AUDIENCE: Thank you.
观众：谢谢
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
No problem.
没问题
So the FPS controller, if we take a look at it--
所以FPS控制器 如果我们看看它--
we talked about it before, briefly.
我们之前简短地谈过这件事
But effectively, it's just a capsule collider,
但实际上 它只是一个胶囊对撞机
which is sort of defying physics, because it's kinematic.
这有点违反物理学 因为它是运动学的
Kinematic with gravity applied to it.
应用重力的运动学
And it has a camera sort of towards the top of it
它的顶部有一个摄像头
where the head is to simulate the perspective of somebody
头部是用来模拟某人的视角
from first person view.
从第一人称的角度来看
And there's some programming involved that
而且有一些编程涉及到
allows you to control it with the keys and the mouse,
允许你用按键和鼠标来控制它
to control the camera's rotation with the mouse and the position
使用鼠标和位置控制相机的旋转
of the collider with the WASD keys.
对撞机和WASD密钥
And if you want, you can dig into the actual script for it, too.
如果你愿意 你也可以深入研究它的实际脚本
They're all included with the standard assets pack.
它们都包括在标准资产包中
When you import that into your project, it
当您将其导入到项目中时 它会
comes with all the scripts that make all that possible.
附带了使这一切成为可能的所有脚本
I haven't dug through all of them in too much detail, but it's all there for you
我还没有详细地研究过它们 但它们都在那里等着您
if curious as to how it works.
如果对它的工作原理感到好奇
And so if you want to get just a simple FPS controller in your game,
因此 如果你想在游戏中只有一个简单的FPS控制器
a character in your game, to walk around and play a first person game,
游戏中的一个角色 走来走去 玩第一人称游戏
it takes about a minute to get up and running.
启动和运行大约需要一分钟
Now, there's a lot of customization that you
现在 您可以进行大量的定制
can apply to your character controller to make it
可以应用到您的角色控制器以使其
not just the standard, basic character.
不仅仅是标准的、基本的性格
So you can set a walk speed, you can set a run speed.
所以你可以设定步行速度 也可以设定跑步速度
You can set jump speed, you can set the sensitivity of the mouse look
你可以设置跳跃速度 可以设置鼠标的敏感度
on the game-- on the FPS controller.
在游戏上--在FPS控制器上
You can apply what's called FOV kick, which means when you're sprinting--
你可以应用所谓的FOV打腿 这意味着当你在冲刺时--
which it allows you to sprint with pressing Shift,
它允许你按下Shift键进行冲刺
which multiplies your speed--
这会使你的速度成倍增长--
it'll actually-- it'll expand your depth of field a little bit to make it
它实际上--它会把你的景深扩大一点 以使它
look as if you're kind of claustrophobic.
看起来你好像有点幽闭恐惧症
Things kind of go out, and so it looks more narrow,
东西就像是在外面 所以它看起来更窄
and it kind of gives you that look as if you're sprinting down a path,
它让你看起来就像是在一条小路上冲刺
and you can set just how much it increases by.
你可以设置它增加了多少
You can see the curve of how that is applied here.
您可以看到这条曲线是如何在这里应用的
So this is one of the components that Unity allows you to do,
这是Unity允许您执行的组件之一
is there's a curve object, and you can use this curve
有一条曲线物体 你可以用这条曲线
to influence various things in your game.
在你的游戏中影响各种东西
I actually haven't used it much, myself.
实际上 我自己也没怎么用过它
But if you're looking for something to apply a curve to,
但如果你在寻找可以应用曲线的东西
Unity has an interface for making that visible within your inspector.
Unity有一个界面 可以让它在您的检查器中可见
Head bob, which means when I walk, should the camera kind of
头部鲍勃 这意味着当我走路时 摄像机是否应该
go up and down?
上上下下？
When you do have a head bob, what's the curve look like?
当你有一个波波头时 曲线是什么样子的？
So here's another curve.
这是另一条曲线
This is sort of what the head bob looks like, kind
这就是波波头的样子 有点像
of a sine wave but a little bit distorted.
一个正弦波 但有一点失真
And a few other things.
还有其他几件事
So, for example, footstep sounds.
例如 脚步声
Maybe you don't like the sounds that come by default with the controller,
也许你不喜欢控制器默认的声音
so you give it your own footstep sounds.
所以你给它发出你自己的脚步声
Super easy to do.
超级容易做到
Just drag new sounds here.
只需将新声音拖到此处
Jump sound and a landing sound.
跳跃声和落地声
Two more sounds that you can add to it.
你还可以再加上两个声音
And that'll allow you to customize most of the feel of how your character moves
这将允许您自定义角色如何移动的大部分感觉
around in terms of just a basic FPS controller.
就只有一个基本的FPS控制器而言
And so just by applying those very basic things, customized them a little bit--
所以只要应用这些非常基本的东西 对它们进行一点定制--
we got lucky with this maze.
我们在这迷宫里很幸运
And this means that the maze went all the way around and then
这意味着迷宫绕了一圈
looped right back to where we were and ended there.
回到了我们所在的地方然后在那里结束了
So this is-- that's that maze, OK.
这就是那个迷宫
I'm going to go ahead and turn up the sound.
我要把声音调大
You can hear the footsteps, right?
你能听到脚步声 对吧？
Along with the creepy whispering.
伴随着令人毛骨悚然的低语声
But the footsteps are just provided to us by the FPS controller,
但是脚步声只是由FPS控制器提供给我们的
and again, you can customize those to be whatever you want.
你也可以根据自己的需要来定制
And so this gives you the ability to walk around
所以这给了你四处走动的能力
in your scene for a first person view.
在场景中以第一人称视图显示
It doesn't really give you much more than that.
它并没有给你更多
In order to do an FPS where you have maybe a gun or a weapon or something,
为了做一个FPS游戏 你可能有一把枪或武器或什么的
you need to program some more things and it's a lot more complicated.
你需要编写更多的程序 这要复杂得多
But for just basic navigation of a 3D scene, it's a great foundation,
但对于3D场景的基本导航来说 这是一个很好的基础
a great way to get started.
一个很好的开始
So any question as to how the FPS controller works?
那么 有没有关于FPS控制器如何工作的问题？
There are other controllers, too.
还有其他的控制器
There are third-person controllers.
有第三人称控制器
So if you want to use those.
如果你想使用这些
They don't come with a camera-- based on my experimentation,
它们不带摄像头--根据我的实验
they don't actually come with a camera by default.
它们并没有默认的摄像头
So I think you have to parent a camera to them in the way
所以我觉得你得给他们装个摄像头
that you want for your game.
你想要的游戏
Like, for example, some games have the camera super high above your character
比如说 有些游戏的摄像头比你的角色高得多
while you're walking around, and some of them
当你四处走动的时候
have a behind the shoulder look, almost like Fortnite or Gears
有一个肩膀后面的外观 几乎像Fortnite或齿轮
of War, really close to the character.
战争 真的很接近角色
And then some kind of have-- like in Banjo Kazooie,
然后是某种有--就像班卓卡祖伊
you could be walking up a mountain and so the camera
你可能在爬山 所以相机
is kind of like perpendicular to where you are, and sort of follows you.
就像是垂直于你所在的位置 并跟随着你
Around so camera programming for 3D characters
围绕这样的相机编程的3D人物
is a little bit more complicated than it is for first person games.
比第一人称游戏要复杂一些
And so that's why I mentioned it doesn't come with a camera by default,
这就是为什么我提到它默认不带摄像头
so it can be a little bit more complicated.
所以可能会更复杂一点
But I do believe there are a lot of assets on the asset store
但我相信资产商店里有很多资产
that can help bootstrap you if you're getting a programmatic camera
这可以帮助你引导你 如果你有一个可编程的摄像头
setup going for your character in a third-person view.
在第三人称视图中设置您的角色
Yeah.
嗯
AUDIENCE: I've noticed when you're walking around your maze,
观众：我注意到当你在迷宫里走来走去时
occasionally you're clipping the wall and kind of seeing what's behind it.
偶尔 你会剪下这堵墙 有点像是看到了它背后的东西
COLTON OGDEN: Yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
That-- I believe that's a result of the collider being a little bit too big.
我认为这是因为对撞机有点太大了
So what he said was that walking through the maze,
所以他说的是 穿过迷宫
you can kind of clip through the wall a little bit.
你可以稍微剪穿这堵墙
Let's see if you can actually experience it.
让我们看看你是否真的能体验到它
Yeah, like right there.
对 就像就在那里
Yeah.
嗯
And that's the-- I believe that's just the camera or the collider
这就是--我相信那只是照相机或对撞机
being a little bit too large.
有点太大了
And so we could probably get rid of that altogether just
所以我们可以完全摆脱这一点
by shrinking the collider a little bit.
通过将对撞机缩小一点
Just a detail that I didn't iron out.
只是一个我没有解决的细节
But you'll see that in a lot of games, actually.
但实际上 你会在很多游戏中看到这一点
A lot of games have clipping that you can observe,
许多游戏都有你可以观察到的剪辑
depending on how they program the game.
这取决于他们如何编写游戏程序
But, yeah.
但是 是的
Any other questions as to how character controllers work,
关于角色控制器如何工作的任何其他问题
and how the import process works, and how to get it in your scene?
以及导入过程的工作原理 以及如何将其应用到您的场景中？
OK.
好的
Cool.
凉爽的
Yeah, it's super easy.
是啊 这超级简单
Again, here's what the FPS controller looks like.
同样 下面是FPS控制器的外观
Capsule collider with a camera.
太空舱与摄像机相撞
And then the third-person controller.
然后是第三人称控制器
By default they give you a pretty nice looking model on the left side
默认情况下 它们会在左侧为您提供一个非常好看的模型
there so that you can experiment with it.
这样你就可以用它做实验了
And then they apparently give you an AI one
然后他们显然会给你一个AI One
as well so you can test AI in your scene with it,
这样你就可以用它在你的场景中测试人工智能
but I haven't experimented too much with that to vouch for how well it works.
但我还没有对此进行过太多的试验 以保证它有多好用
So an important aspect of today's example
所以今天这个例子的一个重要方面
is that we've gone from having just one scene to having two scenes.
我们已经从只有一个场景变成了两个场景
So I want to illustrate how we sort of move between the scenes a little bit.
所以我想说明一下我们是如何在场景之间移动的
And also, I realized we didn't really cover the dungeon generator
而且 我意识到我们并没有真正涵盖地牢发电机
in code detail.
在代码细节上
But notice that I have exposed a lot of things here.
但请注意 我在这里暴露了很多东西
A floor prefab, wall prefab, ceiling prefab.
地板预制件、墙体预制件、天花板预制件
These are just the cubes that are textured
这些只是带有纹理的立方体
to be our floor, walls, and ceiling.
成为我们的地板、墙壁和天花板
We can just click and drag them from the inspector into our scene,
我们只需点击并将它们从检查器拖到我们的场景中
onto the components there.
放在那里的组件上
We have a character controller reference here,
我们这里有一个字符控制器引用
so that we can place the character controller in our scene
这样我们就可以在场景中放置角色控制器
when we've generated the first block.
当我们生成第一个块时
We can basically take the transform and set its position to whatever
我们基本上可以接受变换 并将其位置设置为任何位置
that x z is.
那个x z就是
And then a floor parent and a walls parent.
然后是地板父对象和墙父对象
So the reason that we have parent objects, actually,
所以我们之所以有父对象 实际上
which we didn't look at before--
这是我们之前没有看到的--
whoops, I've lost track of where my--
哎呀 我忘了我的.
there it is.
就是这样
The reason that we have parent objects here
我们在这里拥有父对象的原因
is because when we instantiate all of the cubes in our scene,
是因为当我们实例化场景中的所有立方体时
just sort of just instantiate them without really thinking about it,
只是在某种程度上实例化它们 而不是真正地考虑它
it ends up--
结果是--
basically, I'll show you here.
基本上 我会在这里展示给你看
Well, first of all, I don't know what this is.
首先 我不知道这是什么
I think it's-- that's interesting.
我觉得这--这很有趣
Oh, because I clicked on the floor parent.
哦 因为我点击了楼层家长
Right, OK.
好的 好的
So you click on the walls parent, actually.
因此 实际上 您可以点击墙的父对象
I didn't do that yet, but it will actually
我还没有那么做 但实际上它会的
show you where all of the objects that are parented-- or that
显示所有为父对象的对象的位置--或者
are dependent on that parent.
都依赖于那个父母
So the floor parent here--
所以这里的地板父母--
see how many floor blocks there are?
看到有多少块地板了吗？
It's quite a lot.
这是相当多的
There's a lot of floor blocks here, and in the walls parent there is even more.
这里有很多地砖 而在父母的墙上 还有更多的
There's a lot of walls and ceiling blocks,
有很多墙和天花板
and if we just generate those without assigning them a parent,
如果我们只是生成这些 而不给它们分配一个父代
it'll just fill up our hierarchy there very messily.
它只会非常混乱地填满我们在那里的层级
And it makes navigating our scene during debugging very difficult.
这使得在调试期间导航我们的场景变得非常困难
We don't need to see that we have a million clones of the floor
我们不需要看到我们有一百万个克隆的地板
or the ceiling blocks or the wall blocks.
或者天花板积木或墙体积木
And so what we do is we just take all of the cloned blocks and we just parent
因此 我们要做的就是获取所有克隆数据块并将其作为父数据块
them to an object.
将它们添加到一个对象
And when you parent something to an object, you get that little drop-down.
当您将某个对象设置为父对象时 您会看到一个小下拉列表
Like, for example, this first-person character.
比如 这个第一人称角色
This FPS controller is the parent of this first-person character.
该FPS控制器是该第一人称角色的父角色
And so those are two separate objects that both comprise the FPS controller,
因此 这是两个独立的对象 它们都构成了FPS控制器
effectively.
有效地
A parent is top-level, and its children are therefore within this little arrow
父级是顶级的 因此它的子级在这个小箭头中
here, and it's collapsible.
在这里 它是可折叠的
All of the things within the play scene, for example--
例如 游戏场景中的所有东西--
the play scene is the parent to all of these.
游戏场景是所有这些的父场景
It's sort of like a folder hierarchy type of thing.
它有点像文件夹层次结构类型的东西
And so if you want to clean up your scene,
所以如果你想清理你的场景
if you're instantiating a ton of things, just effectively
如果你要实例化一大堆东西 只要有效地
containerize them by putting them into a parent object.
通过将它们放入父对象来对它们进行容器处理
And so we do that in our game with a function called create child prefab.
因此 我们在游戏中使用了一个名为Create Child Prefab的功能来做到这一点
And so what create child prefab does is, it does an instantiation as normal.
因此 创建子预置所做的是 它照常进行实例化
Creates a prefab, instantiates it, gives it a position xyz.
创建一个预制件 实例化它 给它一个位置xyz
Quaternion dot identity because we don't want to apply any rotation to it.
四元数点恒等式 因为我们不想对它应用任何旋转
But my prefab dot transform dot parent equals parent dot transform.
但我的预制点变换父点等于父点变换
Effectively linking our-- we're assigning
有效地将我们的--我们正在分配
the parent field of that prefab's transform to the parent's transform.
预设器转换为父转换的父字段
And that has the effect of basically linking them together
这样做的效果就是把它们联系在一起
in a parent-child relationship.
在亲子关系中
And that will allow us to collapse and expand a list when
这将允许我们在以下情况下折叠和展开列表
one parent has a bunch of children.
一位家长有一群孩子
We can expand and contract in the hierarchy view and save us a lot of--
我们可以在层次结构视图中展开和收缩 为我们节省了大量--
save us a bit of a headache in terms of navigating our scene
在场景导航方面为我们省去了一点头痛
or we instantiate a lot of things, which is fairly normal.
或者我们实例化了很多东西 这是很正常的
So the actual may--
所以实际情况可能是--
I'll go over this fairly quickly.
我会很快地回顾一下这一点
It's a fairly simple algorithm.
这是一个相当简单的算法
And we talked about it on the screen, and we don't have a ton of time.
我们在屏幕上讨论了这件事 我们没有太多的时间
But basically we go z to x.
但基本上我们是从z到x
The reason that we go z to x is because in Unity, z and x are
我们从z到x的原因是因为在单位中 z和x是
sort of like the ground axes, and a y is sort of like that up and down axis.
有点像地轴 而a y 有点像上下轴
And so we don't want to instantiate-- we're not
所以我们不想实例化--我们不会
really worried about navigating the y-axis during our maze generator.
真的很担心在我们的迷宫生成器中导航y轴
Because all we're going to do is instantiate four blocks
因为我们要做的就是实例化四个块
on the y-axis during that phase.
在那个阶段的y轴上
So we're basically taking our 2D array, and we're iterating over it xy,
所以我们基本上是拿我们的二维数组 我们迭代它xy
and then we're mapping that to Unity's xz, If that makes sense.
然后我们将其映射到Unity的XZ 如果这有意义的话
Because notice the-- this is our ground, right?
因为注意--这是我们的地盘 对吧？
So where this transform is, you can see the ground, how this is x.
所以在这个变换的位置 你可以看到地面 这是怎样的x
The blue is z.
蓝色是z
And y is this axis here.
Y是这里的轴
We're generating-- we're effectively only concerned about generating
我们正在产生--我们实际上只关心产生
on the ground, and then when we generate a wall we just
在地面上 然后当我们产生一堵墙时 我们只是
generate it four blocks high on the y.
在y线上四个街区高的地方生成它
We don't think about the y.
我们不考虑y
So that's why x and y for our 2D array, but x
这就是为什么我们的二维数组是x和y 但x
and z for applying that array to Unity's 3D coordinate system.
以及z 用于将该数组应用于Unity的3D坐标系
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
OK.
好的
So we're iterating over z and x.
所以我们在z和x上迭代
And then we're indexing into our map data, z and x, which
然后我们索引到我们的地图数据z和x 这
is exactly the same thing as y and x.
与y和x完全是一回事
And then we are creating a child prefab.
然后 我们正在创建一个儿童预制件
If map data z x.
如果地图数据z x
So recall that our map data is a 2D array of Booleans.
回想一下 我们的地图数据是一个二维布尔数组
And so if we have map data z x equal to true, that means there's a wall there.
所以如果我们的地图数据z x等于真 那就意味着那里有一堵墙
It means that there's a true in our array,
这意味着我们的数组中有一个真的
so we should instantiate a wall at that location.
因此 我们应该在该位置实例化一堵墙
So we create three wall prefabs, assign them to the walls parent
因此 我们创建了三个墙预制板 将它们分配给墙父节点
so that they get containerized within there
这样它们就会被装在里面
so they don't clog up our hierarchy view.
这样它们就不会妨碍我们的层次结构视图
And then-- let me see here.
然后--让我看看这个
And so if we don't--
所以如果我们不--
So if we've gone to our maze, if we're generating our maze,
所以 如果我们已经走进了迷宫 如果我们正在生成迷宫
and we get to our first tile that's actually not a wall,
我们看到的第一块瓷砖实际上不是一堵墙
so it's an empty space--
所以这是一个空旷的空间--
So basically, the else here.
所以基本上 这里的其他部分
So if mapped data zx is not true, it's going to be false.
因此 如果映射数据ZX不为真 那么它也将为假
So if that's the case, and if not character placed--
因此 如果是这样的话 如果没有放置字符--
so character placed is just a Boolean.
因此 放置的字符只是一个布尔值
It's a private Boolean.
这是一个私人布尔值
We don't want this to be visible in our inspector.
我们不希望这在我们的检查员中可见
There's no purpose for it to be visible in our inspector.
让它在我们的检查员身上出现是没有意义的
This is just a Boolean for us to use in our script.
这只是我们在脚本中使用的布尔值
So we set that to false by default because we
因此 我们默认将其设置为FALSE 因为我们
haven't placed our character yet.
还没有把我们的角色放进去
But when we generate our maze, we have to make
但当我们产生迷宫时 我们必须
sure we put our character in a spot that there isn't a wall.
当然 我们把我们的角色放在了一个没有墙的地方
Because we obviously don't want him trapped in a wall
因为我们显然不想让他被困在墙里
or clipping through the maze, right?
或者在迷宫中穿行 对吧？
So if not character placed, we're going to set the character controller's
因此 如果没有放置字符 我们将设置字符控制器的
transform.
变形
We're going to sense position and rotation, which is a function.
我们将感知位置和旋转 这是一个函数
We're going to set it to x and then y 1, and then z.
我们要把它设为x 然后是y1 然后是z
And then no rotation, so quaternion dot identity.
然后没有旋转 所以四元数点的身份
And then set that to true.
然后将其设置为真
So therefore, this will never be called again.
因此 这将永远不会再被调用
So this only gets called on that very first empty space
因此 这只在第一个空格上调用
that we go through our maze.
我们要穿过迷宫
And that's it for that.
就这样了
When we-- no matter what we do, whether there's a wall in our maze or not,
当我们--不管我们做什么 不管迷宫里有没有墙
we're going to want to generate a floor and a ceiling at that space.
我们会想要在那个空间创造一个地板和一个天花板
So-- that's, of course, assuming that generate roof
所以--当然 这是假设产生屋顶
is true which, recall, we made a public Boolean in our inspector
是真的吗 回想一下 我们在检查器中公开了一个布尔值
so that I could debug and show you guys what the maze looks like from up above.
这样我就可以调试并向你们展示从上面看迷宫是什么样子
So if generate roof--
因此 如果生成屋顶--
create a child prefab for ceiling prefab of x 4 z, so a bit higher up.
为x 4 z的天花板预制板创建子预制板 因此稍微高一点
And then no matter what, always want a floor.
然后不管怎样 总是想要一层楼
So create a floor prefab at x 0 z.
因此 在x 0 z处创建地板预制板
So down below.
所以在下面
And our character controller gets placed at, recall, x 1 z,
我们的角色控制器被放置在 Recall x1 z
so just above the floor.
所以就在地板上方
The assignment is actually-- part of the assignment
作业实际上是--作业的一部分
is generate a hole in the floor.
在地板上挖个洞
And if there's a hole in the floor and the character falls through the hole,
如果地板上有个洞 角色从洞里掉了下来
should get a game over, right?
比赛应该结束了 对吧？
So you're going to need to create a game over scene
所以你需要在场景上创建一个游戏
or we need to transition to that scene.
或者我们需要过渡到那个场景
And then we're going to need to check to see whether the character's transform
然后我们需要检查角色的变形
has gone below a certain amount.
已经跌破了一定的数量
It's all fairly easy stuff to do.
这都是相当容易做的事情
But you'll look to do some of that in here.
但你会希望在这里做一些这样的事情
And then the actual maze data function is here.
然后实际的迷宫数据函数就在这里
I won't go over it in detail, but it's the algorithm
我不会详细介绍它 但它是算法
that we talked about before, where we choose direction to move randomly,
我们之前谈过的 我们选择随机移动的方向
and we choose a random number of steps to move,
我们随机选择一些步数来移动
clamp that value within the constraints of the maze,
把这个值限制在迷宫的约束范围内
and then set every tile that we explore to false.
然后将我们探索的每一块瓷砖都设置为假
And that has the effect of creating the maze.
这就产生了创造迷宫的效果
And then we just return that data back to our function as just a 2D array.
然后我们只需将该数据作为2D数组返回给我们的函数
Notice that in C Sharp, to create a 2D array,
请注意 在C Sharp中 要创建2D数组
it's a little bit different than in a lot of other languages.
它与许多其他语言有一点不同
It has its own set of syntax for that.
对于这一点 它有自己的一套语法
You have the array syntax that you're probably familiar with,
您可能已经熟悉了数组语法
but then you also have this comma.
但是你还有这个逗号
And that comma is to designate that there are two arguments to that index
这个逗号表示该索引有两个参数
syntax here.
这里有语法
Just means an x should go here and a y should go there, basically.
基本上就是说x应该放在这里 y应该放在那里
Or y, x.
或者y x
And that's 2D array.
这就是二维数组
And you can make it as many degrees as you want to.
你可以把它变成你想要的任何一个学位
Just add more commas to it.
只需添加更多逗号即可
And notice that to actually allocate the memory that we want for that 2D array--
注意 要为这个2D数组实际分配我们想要的内存--
new bool, maze size, maze size.
新布尔 迷宫大小 迷宫大小
So our maze is always square shaped.
所以我们的迷宫总是方形的
Same-- and you could easily make this maze
同样的--你可以很容易地做出这个迷宫
x, maze y if you wanted to, to make it rectangular.
X 迷宫y 如果你想的话 把它变成矩形
So you need to have two public variables instead of one.
因此 您需要有两个公共变量 而不是一个
And all of this is fairly visible to the inspector, too.
而所有这一切对检查员来说也是相当明显的
In our dungeon generator you can see I made a tiles to remove, 350.
在我们的地牢发电机中 你可以看到我做了一个要移除的瓷砖 350
So that means that our maze is going to cut out 350 tiles,
这意味着我们的迷宫将切割出350块瓷砖
and as soon as it cuts out 350 tiles, it's done.
一旦切割出350块瓷砖 它就完成了
And then our maze size is 30 by 30.
然后我们的迷宫大小是30乘30
So that means there's going to be 900 tiles in our maze.
这意味着我们的迷宫里将会有900块瓷砖
So you can tailor this to whatever you want in order
所以你可以为你想要的任何东西量身定做
to produce sparse or denser mazes to your liking.
根据您的喜好生成稀疏或密集的迷宫
So any questions as to how the code for that works?
有什么问题吗 代码是怎么工作的？
More or less.
差不多吧
So now we'll actually get to the scenes part of it.
现在我们来看看场景部分
And so transitioning betw--
所以在两个...
oh, yeah.
哦是的
AUDIENCE: I'm thinking, like, for a smaller
观众：我想 就像 一个小的
game like that, that works great.
像这样的游戏 效果很好
But for a larger game, wouldn't you want to model the walls
但是对于一个更大的游戏 你不想把墙建模吗？
as 2D kind of objects, and the ceiling, instead of a whole cube?
像是2D的物体 天花板 而不是一个整体的立方体？
COLTON OGDEN: Oh, yeah.
科尔顿·奥格登：哦 是的
So for a small game, is it ideal--
所以对于一个小游戏来说 它是理想的吗？
more ideal for the walls to be rendered as one discrete object as opposed
更理想的是将墙壁渲染为一个离散对象
to several cubes?
几个立方体？
Yeah, absolutely.
当然了
That's 100% true.
这是百分之百的正确
And actually, Minecraft is an example of this sort of idea
实际上 《我的世界》就是一个例子
that you think would work, but they actually
你认为可行 但实际上
consolidate all their geometry after they've generated it in this way
用这种方法生成几何图形后
and produce, like, models that are more optimized.
并生产出更优化的模型
You think that you're interacting with this world that's
你认为你在和这个世界互动
a bunch of these little blocks, all separate.
一堆这些小块 都是分开的
But it's actually one big piece of geometry,
但它实际上是一大块几何图形
and then it dynamically figures out where you're hitting and removes
然后它会动态地计算出你击中的位置
and adds blocks as needed.
并根据需要添加块
And there's some cool videos on YouTube as to how to do this in Unity,
YouTube上有一些很酷的视频 介绍如何在Unity中做到这一点
too, which I looked at a long time ago.
我很久以前也看过
And it kind of shows you--
这就像是在告诉你
you can actually dynamically create meshes and vertices and stuff in Unity,
你可以在Unity中动态地创建网格和顶点
and then create objects that way, which is really cool.
然后以这种方式创建对象 这真的很酷
But that's a little bit more on the advanced side.
但这是一个更先进的一面
But yeah, absolutely.
但是 是的 绝对
For an actual implementation of this, a simple but more efficient way
为了实际实现这一点 一个简单但更有效的方法
to do it would just be to have one solid, large, wall object.
要做到这一点 只需要一个坚固的 大的 墙壁物体
That's as tall as you need it to be, and maybe as
你需要它多高就有多高
wide as you need it to be for one character, and have that work.
一个角色需要多大的宽度 就有多大的宽度
But for simplicity's sake and to illustrate the algorithm,
但为了简单起见 为了说明算法
we were just using the cubes.
我们只是在用立方体
Yeah, exactly.
是啊
But yeah, good point.
不过 说得对
That's 100% true.
这是百分之百的正确
All right, multiple scenes.
好吧 多个场景
So the way that we do this--
所以我们这样做的方式--
so I'm going to go into my text editor.
所以我要打开我的文本编辑器
Whoops So the-- grab pick-ups script.
哎呀 所以--抢皮卡脚本
So grab pick-ups is a component that's attached to the character controller,
抓取拾取器是一个连接到角色控制器的组件
because he's going to be picking up pick-ups.
因为他要去接人
And what the grab pick-up script effectively does is,
抓取拾取脚本有效地做的是
the character controller built-in collide
字符控制器内置碰撞
has this function that you can define for it called on-controller collider
有一个你可以定义的函数叫做控制器碰撞器
hits, where anything that collides with the controller's collider
碰撞 任何与控制器的碰撞器碰撞的东西
will trigger this callback function.
将触发此回调函数
And you can grab the information about the object that you collided with
你就能得到你撞到的物体的信息
and then perform some sort of logic on that.
然后在上面执行某种逻辑
And so it's actually calling this function every single time
所以它每次都在调用这个函数
we collide with any of the tiles or the blocks in our scene as well.
我们也会与场景中的任何瓦片或块发生碰撞
There's just no logic to account for them,
只是没有逻辑来解释它们
so it's just effectively an empty function call.
所以它实际上只是一个空函数调用
But if it's the case that the game object has a tag of pick-up--
但是如果游戏对象有一个拾取的标签
which we've set in our Unity editor, and I'll show you how to do that--
我们已经在Unity编辑器中设置好了 我会告诉你怎么做--
then we should play a sound from our pick-up sound source.
那么我们应该播放一个来自拾音声源的声音
And then we should--
然后我们应该
using-- you actually used this in the last lecture,
你在上节课就用过这个
but only within the same scene.
但只是在同一个场景中
We're going to call scene manager dot load scene, play.
我们要叫场景经理点载入场景 播放
And you need Unity engine dot scene management.
你需要Unity引擎点场景管理
Using unity engine dot scene management at the top of your script
在脚本顶部使用Unity引擎点场景管理
in order to use this.
才能用上这个
And load scene effectively just will literally just
和加载场景有效地只是将字面上只是
load a scene by its name.
按名称加载场景
And we're doing that in a couple of places.
我们正在几个地方这样做
So we're actually doing it there.
所以我们真的在那里做
But remember, we had the title scene, which had the same sort of thing.
但请记住 我们有标题场景 其中有同样的事情
You press Enter, and you load the play scene, right?
你按下回车键 然后加载游戏场景 对吗？
So this load scene on input component that I created
我创建的输入组件上的负载场景
is attached to a text field in the title scene.
附加到标题场景中的文本字段
And all we're doing here is in the update,
我们在这里做的就是更新
we're just saying hey, if input dot get access submit is equal to 1,
我们只是说 如果输入点获取访问提交等于1
then scene manager dot load scene play.
然后场景管理器点加载场景播放
Almost the same-- kind of almost the same code, only in this case
几乎相同--几乎相同的代码 只是在本例中
we're querying Unity's input.
我们正在询问Unity的输入
It has a global input manager, get axis.
它有一个全局输入管理器GET AXIS
So it has several axes, is how it defines it.
所以它有几个轴 这是它定义它的方式
Different methods of input.
不同的输入方法
And then it defines them by keywords, so in this case submit is a keyword.
然后它通过关键字来定义它们 所以在本例中Submit是一个关键字
And you define-- you map those keys--
然后你定义--你映射那些键--
or you map those keywords to specific keys and input sources
或者将这些关键字映射到特定的键和输入源
on whatever platform you're targeting.
无论你的目标是什么平台
In this case, submit is synonymous with either Enter or Return,
在这种情况下 提交与Enter或Return同义
depending on which platform we're using.
这取决于我们使用的平台
And it could have other meanings if we're exporting this to Xbox
如果我们将它导出到Xbox 它可能有其他含义
or if we're exporting it to the web, or if we're
或者如果我们要将其输出到网络上 或者如果我们
exporting it to a mobile phone.
将其输出到手机上
There's a lot of different ways it changes.
它有很多不同的变化方式
And so the way that it checks is it will be 0 or 1,
所以它检查的方式是0或1
specifically, so we can say if input dot get access submit
具体地说 所以我们可以说如果输入点获得访问提交
equals 1, scene manager load scene play.
等于1 场景管理器加载场景播放
And it won't let you do if input dot get access submit, because it's explicitly
如果输入不能获得访问提交 它就不允许这样做 因为它显式地
expecting integer and it will throw an error if you're
应为整型 如果为
trying to use it like a Boolean.
试着像使用布尔值一样使用它
So we need to use this equals, equals one to test for equivalence.
所以我们需要使用这个等于 等于1来检验等价性
And that's all we're effectively doing there.
这就是我们在那里有效地做的所有事情
Now, the interesting thing is, when we reload the scene for the pick-up
现在 有趣的是 当我们重新加载场景以进行取景时
for the maze, there's a soundtrack playing in the background.
对于迷宫 背景中播放着一段配乐
And we want the soundtrack to constantly be playing the same thing
我们希望原声带一直播放相同的东西
and to loop, right?
以及循环 对吗？
The sound effect-- we don't want it to start up immediately again
音效--我们不希望它立即再次启动
and start up from the very beginning again.
从头再来
We kind of want this seamless sort of feel to it.
我们有点想要这种无缝的感觉
And so how do we think we can solve this problem?
那么我们认为我们可以如何解决这个问题呢？
AUDIENCE: So it doesn't play again when?
观众：那么它什么时候不会再播放了？
When you reload the scene?
当你重新加载场景的时候？
COLTON OGDEN: Sorry?
科尔顿·奥格登：什么？
AUDIENCE: You don't want it to start over when you reload the scene?
观众：当你重新加载场景时 你不想重新开始吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Correct.
科尔顿·奥格登：正确
So any ideas as to how we would do this?
你有什么想法吗
AUDIENCE: Put level one only in the beginning or something?
观众：把第一级只放在一开始还是什么？
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Well, so whenever we collide with the pickup,
科尔顿·奥格登：嗯 所以每当我们与皮卡相撞时
we reload the scene completely from scratch.
我们从头开始重新加载场景
And so when you reload a scene, it destroys every game object
所以当你重新加载一个场景时 它会破坏所有的游戏对象
in the scene, including all the objects that
在场景中 包括所有的对象
have audio sources attached to them.
都有音频源
And so when it reloads the scene, it reinstantiates
所以当它重新加载场景时
all of the game objects in the scene, including those with audio sources,
场景中的所有游戏对象 包括那些具有音频源的对象
and retriggers their playing.
并重新启动他们的游戏
So what we want to do is prevent this from happening.
所以我们要做的就是防止这种情况发生
AUDIENCE: Just have a counter and when you get the first pickup then
观众：只要有一个柜台 当你得到第一个皮卡 然后
it goes to 1.
就变成了1
And then you say if less than 1, play the sound.
如果小于1 播放声音
COLTON OGDEN: That will have the effect of-- so you're saying have a counter,
科尔顿·奥格登：这将产生这样的效果--所以你是说有一个计数器
and when--
当...
AUDIENCE: Or, yeah.
观众：是的
True-false would do.
真-假就行了
Boolean would be better at this.
布尔在这方面会更好
COLTON OGDEN: So have a counter or true-false when you load the scene,
科尔顿奥格登：所以有一个计数器或真假当你加载场景
it starts the music.
就会开始放音乐
But what happens when we reload the scene from scratch
但是当我们从头开始重新加载场景时会发生什么呢
and the audio that was playing gets deleted?
播放的音频被删除了吗
AUDIENCE: Can you transport certain objects between scenes?
观众：你能在场景之间转移某些物体吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Can you transport
科尔顿·奥格登：你能在场景之间转移某些物体吗？
Effectively, you can.
实际上 你可以
There is a function called don't destroy on load, actually.
实际上 有一个函数叫做don 't destroy on load
So what that d-- it's a Unity function, which
所以这个d是一个统一函数
allows you to preserve an object as it is between scenes.
允许您在场景之间保留对象
So if you don't want your object with the music to destroy itself and then
所以如果你不想让你的音乐对象自我毁灭
reinstantiate on load--
重新加载-
well, technically, just don't destroy itself.
严格来说 就是别自毁
Just do don't destroy on load at the game object.
只是不要在加载时破坏游戏对象
And so this don't destroy, we apply this to our audio source--
所以这不会破坏 我们把它应用到我们的音频源上--
our whisper source, it's called--
我们的耳语来源 叫做
in the scene.
在场景中
The only problem with this is if we reinstantiate--
唯一的问题是如果我们重新
or if we don't destroy on load this object, it's going to persevere.
或者如果我们没有在加载时摧毁这个物体 它会继续存在
But when we reload the scene, it's going instantiate a new one.
但当我们重新加载场景时 它将实例化一个新的场景
So what's the effect of this going to be?
那么这将会产生什么影响呢？
We're going to have two audio sources playing at the same time.
我们将同时播放两个音频源
What happens when we do another one?
如果我们再做一次会发生什么？
You're going to have three audio sources playing at the same time.
您将同时播放三个音频源
So for every time you go to a next level,
所以每一次你进入下一个阶段
you're going to add the same audio track to the scene.
您将向场景中添加相同的音轨
It's going to be very annoying very quickly.
很快就会变得非常恼人
The way that we avoid this happening is by making what's called a singleton.
我们避免这种情况发生的方法是通过创建所谓的单例
So what a singleton is is a class that can only effectively
因此 单例是一个只能有效地
be instantiated one time.
被实例化一次
And we do this by creating a static variable here called don't destroy.
我们通过在这里创建一个名为不要销毁的静态变量来实现这一点
No, we call it instance, which is of type don't destroy.
不 我们称它为实例 它的类型是不破坏
So it's this component here, right?
所以这就是这个组件 对吗？
And so the don't destroy class as a whole has
所以不要破坏阶级作为一个整体
this static variable called instance.
这个静态变量称为实例
And we set it to null by default. And we haven't instantiated
默认情况下 我们将其设置为NULL 我们还没有实例化
a don't destroy component yet.
A暂时不要销毁组件
And what this ensures, in our scene, by the logic
在我们的场景中 通过逻辑 这确保了什么
we have in the awake function, awake is almost the same thing as start.
在唤醒功能中 唤醒和启动几乎是一回事
It just means whenever-- you can pause an object
它的意思是无论何时--你可以暂停一个对象
and it will awake from its pause state.
它将从暂停状态中唤醒
But awake also gets called when an object gets instantiated.
但是 当对象被实例化时 也会调用唤醒
So if the instance is set to null on awake, instance equals this,
因此 如果实例在唤醒时设置为空 则实例等于以下值
so this don't destroy.
所以这不会毁了你
So whatever this is being called from, this
所以 无论这是从哪里打来的 这
don't destroy will be the instance.
不破坏将是一个例子
Whenever the first don't destroy component is in our scene.
只要第一个不破坏组件就在我们的场景中
The very first maze that we generate.
我们制造的第一个迷宫
The sound source instance will be this.
声源实例将如下所示
And then we set don't destroy on load for the game object that
然后我们为游戏对象设置了加载时不破坏
is holding that don't destroy or don't destroy component, that audio source.
持有不破坏或不破坏分量的音频源
But if the instance is not equal to this, so if we've awoken
但是如果实例不等于这个 那么如果我们已经唤醒
and this is level 2, for example, instance
这是2级 例如
is going to be set to the don't destroy component on the don't destroy on load
将设置为加载时不销毁组件上的不销毁组件
object that we created in the first maze.
我们在第一个迷宫中创建的对象
Because we did this logic here.
因为我们在这里做了这个逻辑
And so it's going to try and instantiate a second don't destroy component.
所以它会尝试实例化第二个 不要破坏组件
It's going to destroy another sound source.
它会摧毁另一个声源
But instance is not going to be null.
但实例不会为空
Instance is going to be equal to that first object.
实例将等于第一个对象
So we say, if instance is not equal to this, destroy game object.
所以我们说 如果实例不等于这个 就销毁游戏对象
So this is going to be from the standpoint of the second don't
所以这将是从第二个角度来看 不要
destroy that got created.
摧毁被创造出来的东西
AUDIENCE: So a singleton basically persists.
观众：所以基本上都是单身汉
COLTON OGDEN: The singleton will persist indefinitely
科尔顿·奥格登：独生子女将无限期存在
upon its first instantiation.
在其第一次实例化时
And there will only ever be one singleton.
而且永远只有一个独生子女
This is a very basic, very common pattern
这是一个非常基本、非常常见的模式
in software engineering for ensuring they only
在软件工程中 以确保它们仅
have one object of a given type present throughout your entire project.
在整个项目中呈现一个给定类型的对象
But this is how we prevent multiple sound sources from being instantiated.
但这就是我们防止实例化多个声源的方法
We always ensure that only one object with that component
我们始终确保只有一个具有该组件的对象
gets instantiated at once, and any future instantiations of that object
被一次实例化 并且该对象将来的任何实例化
get destroyed immediately, assuming that they aren't that first object.
假设它们不是第一个物体 立即被销毁
If they are that first object, instance will not--
如果它们是第一个对象 实例将不会--
instance will equal this, and so it will still skip this part,
实例将等于该值 因此它仍将跳过这一部分
and so it will stay alive.
因此 它将继续存在
So any questions as to how the persevering through multiple scenes
所以任何关于如何在多个场景中坚持下去的问题
works for a sound source?
为音源工作吗？
OK.
好的
That's how we get multiple scenes.
这就是我们如何获得多个场景的原因
So fog.
好大的雾
We looked at fog already, but I have a few screenshots here
我们已经看到了雾 但我这里有几个截图
to kind of help illustrate what fog has looked like over the years.
以帮助说明这些年来雾的样子
So fog looks pretty unconvincing in this screenshot.
因此 在这张截图中 雾看起来很难令人信服
This is Turok for the N64.
我是N64的图罗克
It's just-- kind of looks as if, you know, sort of at a certain distance,
它只是--看起来 你知道 在一定的距离上
a very dense sheet of fog has appeared.
出现了一层非常浓密的雾
And you can actually make this happen in Unity by setting the--
实际上 你可以通过设置--
there's a curve, a fog curve that I believe you
有一条曲线 一条雾曲线 我相信你
can manipulate that will effectively--
可以有效地操纵它--
the algorithm that determines how the color gets summed to things
确定如何将颜色与事物相加的算法
far away is very fast as opposed to gradual or linear.
远距离是非常快的 而不是渐变的或线性的
So you can make it just exponential, effectively,
所以你可以让它成为指数级的 有效的
and make it look as if the fog is incredibly dense
让它看起来像是浓雾密布
and starts almost at a very fixed spot and have
几乎从一个非常固定的位置开始 并且
the rest of this area in front of you look normal.
你面前这个区域的其余部分看起来都很正常
Here is another example--
这是另一个例子--
Star Wars Shadows of the Empire, one of my favorite N64 games
《星球大战帝国之影》是我最喜欢的N64游戏之一
which has the same look.
有着相同的外貌
And so in this era, you can see fog is very distinguishable.
所以在这个时代 你可以看到雾是非常清晰的
Very artificial looking, because it's very tinted.
看起来很做作 因为它的颜色很深
In this case it looks very blue.
在这种情况下 它看起来非常蓝色
In this case it looks very pale blue.
在这种情况下 它看起来非常淡蓝色
This is Silent Hill.
这里是寂静山
And Silent Hill looks realer, more realistic,
而寂静山看起来更真实 更现实
but kind of the same thing at play here.
但在这里也在发挥着同样的作用
You have a very pale gray metallic blue color, and the density in this case
你有一种非常淡的灰色金属蓝色 在这种情况下 密度
is very high.
非常高
The density is much higher.
密度要高得多
Well, maybe close to as high as it is in our game that we're showing today.
嗯 也许接近我们今天展示的游戏中的最高水平
But it's effectively the same thing, just with a different color.
但它实际上是一样的 只是颜色不同
And they use it to great effect in here, not only for sort of this aesthetic
他们在这里使用它产生了很大的影响 不仅仅是为了这种美感
to make you look as if you're in some sort of desolate town.
让你看起来像是在某个荒凉的小镇上
But also to dynamically load objects or to prevent rendering objects
还可以动态加载对象或防止渲染对象
that are a certain distance away.
都在一定距离之外
And to optimize performance on hardware that was severely
并优化严重受影响的硬件性能
limited at the time, which was Playstation 1, which
当时是有限的 这是PlayStation1 它
is a fairly weak console.
是一个相当弱的游戏机
And then here is Shadow of the Colossus for PS4, which just came out
然后是刚刚上映的PS4的巨人之影
not too long ago, and we can see fog is still being
不久前 我们可以看到雾还在继续
used but it looks photo-realistic.
它是二手的 但看起来很逼真
And there's probably a lot more that they're
而且可能还有更多的东西
doing they probably have several layers of fog,
它们可能有好几层雾
they probably have textures and transparent objects
它们可能有纹理和透明对象
that are simulating fog, and a lot of more complicated things like that.
它们在模拟雾 以及许多更复杂的东西
Fog that only hangs at a certain distance
只在一定距离处悬挂的雾
so it looks like fog going over the lake.
所以看起来像是湖面上有雾
There's a lot of things here, but it's the same idea.
这里有很多东西 但这是一个概念
And they probably have the same sort of foundational base
它们很可能有相同的基础
fog present throughout the scene.
整个现场都有雾
And then here's our game, just to show how it looks.
这是我们的游戏 只是为了展示一下它的样子
You can barely even see it.
你几乎看不到它
But it does give you this sort of, like, lost
但它确实让你有一种迷失的感觉
in a really dangerous maze feeling, which-- and it's super easy to do.
在一种非常危险的迷宫感觉中 这--这非常容易做到
And it can save you performance and it can add a lot of aesthetic
它可以节省您的性能 还可以增加许多美感
to your game.
为了你的比赛
And so the last big thing we'll talk about today is Unity 2D, actually.
因此 我们今天要讨论的最后一件大事实际上是Unity 2D
So I'm going to go back into--
所以我要回到--
oh, questions about fog.
哦 关于雾的问题
I know that was a pretty high-level overview.
我知道这是一个相当高层次的概述
Over looked at we looked at how it applies
我们看了一下它是如何应用的
in the settings and questions as to how it works or how to get work in Unity?
关于它是如何工作的 或者如何在Unity中找到工作的设置和问题？
OK.
好的
So we're going to go ahead and look at our title scene.
所以我们要继续 看看我们的片名场景
And so we looked at this earlier, briefly,
所以我们在前面简单地看了一下
but I want to go ahead and show you the components.
但我想继续向你们展示组件
So I'm going to take a look at our canvas.
所以我要看看我们的画布
If you double-click on something you'll zoom out.
如果你双击某个东西 你就会缩小
And so it will automatically detect sort of what your resolution is
所以它会自动检测你的分辨率是什么
and scale the canvas accordingly in your scene view.
并在场景视图中相应地缩放画布
There's a 2D button here.
这里有一个2D按钮
I'm going to go ahead and go to my default layout.
我将继续并转到我的默认布局
I'm going to click on the canvas.
我要点击画布
Notice that it shifted things a little bit because now I have a larger
请注意 它改变了一些东西 因为现在我有了一个更大的
window that's going to be rendered to.
要渲染到的窗口
I'm going to click on the canvas, and then I'm going to go to 2D mode.
我要点击画布 然后进入2D模式
And then notice when you click on 2D and 3D mode,
然后请注意 当您点击2D和3D模式时
you go instantly into seeing it as if you're manipulating it
你马上就能看到它 就好像你在操纵它
in a 2D engine versus a 3D engine.
在2D引擎和3D引擎中
And then going back to 3D, now it's a three-dimensional plane
然后回到3D 现在它是一个三维平面
that you're actually looking at.
你实际上看到的是
So in 2D mode, you can easily sort of navigate it, right click and drag it
因此 在2D模式下 您可以轻松地导航它 右键单击并拖动它
around.
四处转转
I'm going to go here, like this.
我要走到这里 就像这样
And these are very simple components that you can just
这些都是非常简单的组件 您可以
interact with as a GUI.
以图形用户界面的形式与交互
Now, the main thing that you need to get any of this to work
现在 你需要做的主要事情是让这些东西发挥作用
is the canvas, which is here.
就是画布 就在这里
So if you right click and then go to UI, you can go to canvas, if you want to,
因此 如果您右键单击 然后转到UI 您可以转到Canvas 如果您愿意
or you can just add any of these things that you want,
或者你可以添加任何你想要的东西
and it will automatically add a canvas for you.
它会自动为你添加一个画布
Because a canvas is necessary for all of the Unity UI rendering stuff.
因为所有的Unity UI渲染都需要一个画布
So if I were to just add a text on an empty scene,
因此 如果我只是在一个空的场景中添加一个文本
it'll just create a new brand new canvas and an event system.
它只会创造一个全新的画布和活动体系
The event system is just how Unity talks to the canvas and all the UI
事件系统就是Unity与画布和所有用户界面对话的方式
elements of your canvas, given mouse and keyboard input and stuff like that.
画布的元素 给鼠标和键盘输入之类的东西
It's nothing that you necessarily have to worry about or use.
它不是你必须担心或使用的东西
But the canvas is the sort of overall container for all GUI stuff
但画布是所有图形用户界面内容的整体容器
that you do.
你就是这么想的
Now if I click on the tile text or the enter text,
现在 如果我点击磁贴文本或回车文本
notice that they are children of the canvas.
请注意 它们是画布的子项
So they are within the canvas.
因此 他们都在画布上
The canvas is their parent.
画布是它们的父对象
The title text, I can move it around.
标题文本 我可以移动它
Notice that it snaps.
请注意 它会捕捉
it's got my snapping functionality.
它有我的抓拍功能
I can set it up there, it will snap to the top.
我可以把它放在那里 它会卡在上面
It'll-- yeah.
它会--是的
It's pretty handy.
这很方便
You can scale the bounding box.
您可以缩放边界框
It doesn't scale the actual text, but the--
它不会缩放实际的文本 但--
notice that I do have right justification,
请注意 我确实有正确的理由
centering, left justification.
居中 左对齐
Those sorts of helping--
那些帮助--
those sort of features.
这类特征
I can increase the font size via slider, so I can immediately
我可以通过滑块增加字体大小 这样我就可以立即
see without having to edit some code and then
无需编辑一些代码即可查看 然后
reload the project what changing some of these values will look like.
重新加载项目 更改其中一些值将是什么样子
I can easily change the color in real time,
我可以很容易地实时改变颜色
so I can get a sense of how that looks.
这样我就能感觉到它看起来是什么样子
If you wanted some sort of slimy, Dread50 look, I guess.
如果你想要一种粘乎乎的 恐怖的50看 我想
And you can also assign materials to as well, which is kind of cool.
还可以将材质指定给 这是一种很酷的方式
Which I haven't explored too much in detail, but you have that option.
我没有太详细地探讨这一点 但你有这个选择
If you want to give it a material instead of a color, materialed font.
如果要为其提供材质而不是颜色 请使用物化字体
Because ultimately, all this stuff is still 3D,
因为归根结底 所有这些东西仍然是3D的
but Unity presents it in a way that makes it look
但Unity以一种让它看起来像是
as if you're interacting with it in 2D.
就像你在2D中与它互动一样
It's pretty nice.
真的很不错
AUDIENCE: When you put it in 2D form, when you hit play,
观众：当你把它变成2D形式 当你点击Play时
it's going to open up to that?
它会向那个敞开大门吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Yep.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
AUDIENCE: And then how do you transition to the rest of the game?
观众：然后你如何过渡到游戏的其他部分呢？
COLTON OGDEN: So the transition to the rest of the game
科尔顿·奥格登：所以过渡到比赛的其他部分
is in the load scene on input here.
是在这里输入的加载场景中
So the script that we looked at earlier.
所以我们之前看过的剧本
So this is assigned to one of those text labels.
因此 这被分配给其中一个文本标签
So I just gave it to the--
所以我就把它给了--
I forget.
我忘了
I think it's the Enter text.
我想是回车文本的问题
So I gave it this load scene on input, just because it's the Enter text,
所以我在输入时给了它这个加载场景 仅仅因为它是Enter文本
it seemed appropriate.
这看起来很合适
Could put it on anything in the scene.
可以把它放在现场的任何东西上
It doesn't matter.
无所谓
As long as it has this update function, which
只要它有这个更新功能
then has this if input dot get access submit equals 1, and then recall--
如果输入点获取访问提交等于1 那么就有这个 然后回想一下--
go into the Project Settings, input.
进入项目设置 输入
All these axes here are defined for you automatically.
所有这些轴都是自动为您定义的
And then you can choose what they map to, but submit, as you can see,
然后 您可以选择它们映射到什么 但提交 如您所见
positive button is return.
肯定按钮是Return
So if submit is equal to 1, when you press Return it will be equal to 1,
因此 如果提交等于1 当您按Return时 它将等于1
effectively.
有效地
And it gets mapped to other buttons, depending on what
它会被映射到其他按钮 具体取决于
input sources you have on your device.
输入您设备上的信号源
But you can check what it is on your computer
但你可以在你的电脑上查看它是什么
just by going to Axes in your Input Manager.
只需转到输入管理器中的轴
So it's, once again, Edit, Project Settings, Input.
所以 再一次 编辑 项目设置 输入
And then you can see all the axes here.
然后你可以看到这里所有的轴
AUDIENCE: So that, the 2D scene, that's just a scene in itself.
观众：所以 2D场景本身就是一个场景
COLTON OGDEN: That's a scene in itself, completely.
科尔顿·奥格登：这本身就是一个场景 完全是
It has a camera, so we are--
它有摄像头 所以我们--
the camera renders-- the thing about canvas
摄像机渲染--关于画布的事情
is it's kind of separate from the camera,
它是一种与摄像机分开的东西
so it gets rendered onto whatever the camera's rendering separately.
所以它被单独渲染到相机渲染的任何东西上
But the camera in this case, what I've done,
但在这种情况下的摄像机 我所做的
because if by default we just render the camera and the UI,
因为如果默认情况下我们只渲染相机和用户界面
it's going to look just like this.
它看起来就像这样
It's going to look like the sky with Dread50 and Press Enter.
它将看起来像是恐怖50的天空 然后按Enter
That's not the aesthetic that we want, so I take the camera,
这不是我们想要的美学 所以我拿着相机
and then you can give it a background.
然后你可以给它一个背景
So by default, the background is that sky, is the skybox.
所以默认情况下 背景是天空 就是天空盒子
And so I set clear flags.
因此 我设置了明确的旗帜
Clear flags are same thing as background.
清晰的旗帜和背景是一样的
So whatever, there's no geometry or anything.
所以不管怎样 没有几何学之类的东西
Clear-- this clear color, clear flag, this
透明--这个清晰的颜色 清晰的旗帜 这个
gets drawn to before any geometry in the scene, basically.
基本上是在场景中的任何几何体之前绘制
So clear flags, solid color in this case,
所以清晰的旗帜 在这种情况下是纯色的
and then just black, using a color picker.
然后是黑色 使用颜色选择器
So super easy, super nice.
所以超级简单 超级美好
And then this UI, this canvas, will get drawn on top of this camera.
然后这个用户界面 这个画布 将被画在这个相机的顶部
So that's what produces the sort of combined effect of having the UI
这就是产生用户界面的综合效果的原因
text and then the black background.
文本 然后是黑色背景
And then that Enter Text, having that component,
然后输入具有该组件的文本
that checks for the submit input because that's what Enter and Return map to.
这将检查提交输入 因为这就是回车和返回映射的位置
That is what lets us transition from the current scene to the play scene.
这就是让我们从当前场景过渡到游戏场景的原因
And so there are a lot of other cool features
所以还有很多其他很酷的功能
that these labels and such have.
这些标签之类的东西
For example, being able to set its anchor position.
例如 能够设置其锚位置
So depending on what device you're shipping to, you might want--
因此 根据您要运送到的设备 您可能需要--
you know you're going to have multiple screen sizes and screen resolutions.
你知道 你将拥有多种屏幕尺寸和屏幕分辨率
So you can say, I want this label to always
所以你可以说 我希望这个标签永远
be at the very top middle of my scene, and I can do this
站在我的场景的最上方 我可以做到
by clicking this little box here, which is the anchor point selector,
通过点击这里的这个小方框 它是锚点选择器
and then just clicking that.
然后点击就可以了
And so that will always anchor Dread50's text to that top middle,
因此 这将始终将DRead50‘S的文本锚定在该中间上方
no matter what our resolution is.
无论我们的决心是什么
It will always be there.
它将永远在那里
And there's a lot that you can do on top of that.
除此之外 你还可以做很多事情
And you can do that with any UI component, just relative positioning
您可以使用任何UI组件执行此操作 只需相对定位即可
depending on the resolution.
根据分辨率的不同
And the nice thing about Unity, too, if you go to Game,
而团结的好处也是 如果你去看游戏
you can actually choose-- sorry, in the second menu--
你实际上可以选择--对不起 在第二个菜单中--
you can choose a lot of aspect ratios.
您可以选择很多纵横比
So 5:04 doesn't look that great.
所以5点04分看起来不太好
4:03 doesn't look that great.
4点03分看起来不太好
16:10, 16:9, and then standalone.
16：10 16：9 然后是独立的
So standalone is the default export size of your platform.
因此 单机版是您平台的默认导出大小
But you can choo-- you can have it--
但你可以选择--你可以拥有--
you can test different resolutions, and you can also add more, too.
您可以测试不同的分辨率 也可以添加更多分辨率
You can add a fixed resolution if you want, or aspect ratio.
您可以添加一个固定的分辨率 如果你想 或纵横比
And do a lot of cool things that way.
用这种方式做很多很酷的事情
So you don't have to necessarily test it physically on different devices.
因此 你不必在不同的设备上进行物理测试
Although it's very good to so you can make sure
虽然这是非常好的 所以你可以确保
that you're not blowing up your hardware.
你不会炸毁你的硬件
But you have that option.
但你有这个选择
So any questions as to how Unity 2D works and how the canvas works
因此 关于Unity 2D如何工作以及画布如何工作的任何问题
or how we've gotten the simple UI to work?
或者我们是如何让简单的用户界面工作的？
Part of the assignment will be-- and we'll take a look at that now,
作业的一部分将是--我们现在就来看看
actually.
事实上
So assignment 9, we talked about this already, about the gaps in the floor.
作业9 我们已经讨论过了 关于地板上的缝隙
But this will be part of the maze generator, right?
但这将是迷宫发电机的一部分 对吗？
Because it's where we generate, ultimately.
因为这是我们最终产生的地方
Or, the generates-- the maze instantiator.
或者 生成--迷宫实例化程序
The actual part of the maze generator that creates the physical maze.
迷宫生成器的实际部分 它创建物理迷宫
But create gaps in the floor.
但会在地板上留下缝隙
And then when the player falls through, approximately two blocks below, which
然后当球员跌倒时 大约在两个街区以下 这
you can set--
你可以设置--
check the transform is-- the y position is less than a certain amount.
检查转换是--y位置小于某个值
It should be less than 0.
它应该小于0
I think it's based on the top part of it.
我认为这是基于它的最高部分
Then you should transition to a new screen that says Game Over.
然后你应该过渡到一个新的屏幕上 上面写着游戏结束
So create a new scene, very similar to the first scene
所以创造一个新的场景 非常类似于第一个场景
that we looked at, which was just the title screen,
我们看到的 这只是标题屏幕
and you can probably copy most of that.
你可能可以复制其中的大部分内容
But that scene should say Game Over, and then pressing
但那一幕应该是游戏结束 然后按下
Enter there should load the tile scene.
进入那里应该加载瓷砖场景
And then, lastly, add a text object to the play
然后 最后 在剧本中添加一个文本对象
scene that just keeps track of how many levels you've navigated through.
这个场景只记录了你通过了多少个关卡
And you can probably do this with some kind of static variable.
你也许可以用某种静态变量来做这件事
But any solution that accomplishes it is welcome.
但任何实现这一目标的解决方案都是受欢迎的
But altogether, all pretty easy pieces to put together.
但总的来说 所有这些都很容易组装在一起
That was this week, which was Dread Halls and our first foray
那是本周 这是恐怖大厅和我们的第一次突袭
into first-person games.
变成了第一人称游戏
Next week we'll look at Portal.
下周我们将介绍门户网站
It won't look necessarily this good, but it will look similar to this.
它看起来不一定会这么好 但看起来会像这样
This is a screenshot from Portal itself.
这是来自门户网站本身的屏幕截图
But we'll look at how we can render to textures,
但我们将研究如何渲染到纹理
how we can cast rays from our character, our first person controller,
我们如何从我们的角色投射光线 我们的第一人称控制器
how we can actually make it look as if we have a weapon or a gun
我们如何才能让它看起来像是我们有武器或枪
or a portal gun, which is not too difficult.
或者是传送枪 这并不太难
You just have two parent, basically, a model to your first-person controller.
你只有两个父母 基本上是第一人称控制器的一个模型
And then, when we walk through a portal, how do we transition from one portal
然后 当我们穿过一个门户时 我们如何从一个门户过渡
to the other portal?
去另一个传送门？
So just a-- you know teleport, your transform to another position.
所以只是--你知道心灵传送 你的变形到另一个位置
But that was that.
但仅此而已
Next week is Portal, and I will see you all next time.
下周是门户网站 我们下次再见